字幕翻译: Lvs
Translated By Lvs
发行网站: http://unity.starwcn.net
=====老鹰出品[Glede]======
Hello, 山下的伙计们
Hello, folks at home.
我离珠峰峰顶只有不到100码了
I'm 100 yards from the top of Mt. Everest.
但说实在的,这样的假期实在太闷了...
Yet there's a part of me
that can't wait to end this silly vacation...
...还不如回去工作来得刺激些
...and get back to work,
where the real challenges await.
先生,您不再考虑一下吗?
Shouldn't you take your age
into consideration, sir?
毕竟,您已经82岁了
After all, you're 82 years old.
我82岁?
Am I 82?
这些数字对我毫无意义,
我的冒险才开始
These numbers mean nothing to me.
My journey through life has just begun.
先生! 先生!
Sir! Sir!
- 暴风雪正在增强
- 情况非常危险
-Oota tells me the storm's getting worse.
-Very, very bad.
我们必须马上下山
We must abandon our ascent and
go down the mountain immediately.
可峰顶就在眼前,小子
We're so very close to the top,
Mr. Puffy Jacket Man.
我要下山了,你最也好下去
I'm heading down now, sir.
I advise you to do the same.
好吧,随便你
All right, so be it.
星期一开会再见,我会带上炸甜圈
See you at the staff meeting on Monday.
And I'll bring the Krispy Kremes!
这悲惨的画面今天一直出现在我们面前
There, once again, the sad footage
we've been watching all day.
Preston Blake，这位可敬的梦想家,
从拥有一家电台变成当今世界的传媒巨子
A beloved visionary who turned a single
radio station into a global media empire...
...离我们而去了,享年82岁.
稍后有详细报道
...Preston Blake, dead at 82. More after this.
您正收看的是Blake新闻网络
You're watching the Blake Broadcasting Network.
Blake媒体公司--即本新闻网络的父公司,
The stock of Blake Media,
the parent company of this network...
...受Blake去世消息的影响,
其股票今早大幅下跌...
...plunged this morning
on the news of Blake's death...
...在Blake的2号人物--Chuck Cedar
发表声明后,股价有所反弹
...but bounced back after a statement
by Blake's longtime number 2, Chuck Cedar.
就算华佗在世...
All the king's horses and all the king's men...
...Preston Blake也不能死而复生
...couldn't save Preston Blake
from becoming a human Popsicle.
据闻，Blake单身一人,
无儿无女，也未定下遗嘱
And sources indicate that Blake, who was
single and had no children, left no will.
那么，谁将会继承公司百分之49的股份...
So who inherits Blake's 49 percent stake
in the company's stock...
...也就是400亿美元呢?
...valued at $40 billion?
我们将与Blake先生周围的每个人接触
包括他的理发师...
We'll discuss that with people close
to Blake, including his longtime barber...
...敬请收看明天的"深入追击"
别错过, 我是Mac McGrath.
...on tomorrow's lnside Access.
Until then, I'm Mac McGrath.
- 拍好没有?
- 拍好了!
-Are we clear?
-Clear!
Babe? Babe在哪儿?
Babe? Where's Babe?
- 我不会放过你的!
- Babe!
-I'll come over and choke you to death.
-Babe!
我要挂电话了
I got to go.
不值一提的理发师!
你就这么点儿本事?
Freaking barber!
That's the best you could get me?
人们通常会和自己理发师聊很多事
People tell everything to their barbers.
他们是20多年的好朋友
He's been his closest confidant
for more than 20 years.
我不会让这家伙上节目,
你最好给我找点更好的东西，要快
I'm not putting this guy on the air.
Get me something better and get it quick.
不然你就有麻烦了
Or it's your ass.
继承人找到没有?
Did we find this heir yet?
马上就会有消息传真过来
We should be getting that information
via fax any minute now.
我正在叫人调查...
I have lawyers looking through birth records...
...全国各地的出生记录,包括波多黎各和关岛
...in all 50 states, Puerto Rico and Guam.
我们还开了一个小小的赌局,
关岛的赔率是1000比1
In fact, we have a little pool going.
Guam's paying off at 1000-1.
你觉得很好玩,是吧?
Is this a joke to you?
一个简单的血缘关系将会决定公司的命运
Some genetic lottery winner
now controls the fate of this company.
我不是这个意思,这的确很让人烦恼
No, I agree. It's troubling.
烦恼? 你满脸的胡子可以叫烦恼
Troubling? Your beard is troubling.
你的破烟斗,还有你的一口黄牙都可以叫烦恼
Your pipe is troubling.
Your yellow teeth are really troubling.
而如果我失去了公司,那就会是"灭顶之灾"
But if I lose control of this company,
it'll be catastrophic.
有谁认识 Mendlesohn医生?
Does anyone know a Dr. Mendlesohn?
恭喜你,你得了结肠痉挛
Congratulations, you have a spastic colon.
原来如此
That would explain a lot.
"Longfellow Deeds."
Chuck,我们应该到了
Chuck, I think we're there.
老天啊,简直是一片野地
My God, it's all green.
瞧啊, 左侧有敌机!
Look at that thing. Fighter pilot on your left.
来啊,把它打下来!
Got that sucker!
你们俩迷路了么?
You guys lost?
我们在找Longfellow Deeds先生
We're looking for somebody: Longfellow Deeds.
那是Deeds的名字吗?
Is that Deeds' first name?
如果你指的是那位Longfellow Deeds先生...
If the Deeds you're referring to
is Longfellow Deeds...
...是的,那是他的名字
...then yes, that is Deeds' first name.
我可不知道Deeds的名字,我还以为是Greg呢
I don't know Deeds' first name. Maybe it's Greg.
- 也许是Longfellow.
- 也许吧
-Maybe it's Longfellow.
-Maybe.
我不清楚,不过我知道有个家伙的名字叫Greg,
要不要我去叫他?
But I don't know. I know another guy
named Greg. You want me to call him?
不用了,谢谢
告诉我们Deeds先生住哪儿行么?
No! Thank you.
Please, just tell us where Deeds lives.
好吧,好吧,别着急!
我带你们去
All right, don't get all hyperactive.
I'll take you straight to him.
请进吧,伙计们
Step right in, fellows.
- 他住批萨饼店?
- 谁会住在批萨饼店里呢！
-He lives at a pizzeria?
-You can't live in a pizzeria.
他住在楼上, 这店是他开的
He lives upstairs. He owns it.
劳驾请问，Deeds先生在么?
Excuse me. Is Mr. Deeds around?
抱歉,他出去送货了,送货的家伙病了
No, I'm sorry, he's out making deliveries.
The regular delivery guy called in sick.
- 你看起来不象有病啊, Murph.
- 哎呀,我忘了自己在装病
-But you don't look too sick, Murph.
-I forgot I was faking sick today.
- 你们俩想把我骗回来,是吧
- Murph, 穿上围裙过来帮忙
-You two tricked me into coming here.
-Murph, put on an apron and give me a hand.
你们合起来耍我,对吧?
You guys played me like a fiddle. Touch?
那么, Deeds太太在么?
Is Mrs. Deeds around?
Deeds 太太?
我看那小子连约会还没试过呢!
Mrs. Deeds?
I don't think that poor boy ever had a date.
- 那他什么时候回来?
- 一定在吃完午饭前,今天是"卡片日"
-Do you know when he'll be back?
-Before lunch is out. Today's Card Day.
- 卡片日?
- Deeds 经常会写一些贺卡
-Card Day?
-Deeds writes greeting cards.
每个星期一, 他会读给大家听,
然后挑一张...
Every Monday, he tries out a few
and then he chooses one...
...寄给贺卡公司
...and sends it to one of the big card companies.
虽然目前，他还没能卖出一张，但...
Now, he hasn't sold any yet, but...
...将来一定会的
...he will.
要来点什么?
You guys need anything else here?
"亲爱的：
"To my sweetheart
"我爱你，全心全意"
"I love you completely, with all my soul
"我和你,就象面包奶油不分离"
"Without you I'm nothing, a butterless roll"
有意思
That's good.
喜欢吗,先生们?
Like that, gentlemen?
Hallmark贺卡公司觉得很不错,
很有发展潜力
Hallmark said it showed potential,
which is pretty cool.
- 你是Longfellow Deeds吗?
- 叫Deeds就行, 朋友
-Longfellow Deeds?
-Just call me Deeds, pal.
别叫Longfellow什么的那么麻烦
Easy with that Longfellow stuff.
我是Chuck Cedar, Blake媒体公司的执行总载
Chuck Cedar, CEO.
这位是Cecil Anderson, 法律主管
Cecil Anderson, General Counsel of Blake Media.
握手太见外了,我们流行拥抱
Handshakes are for strangers.
We hug around here, buddy.
你好吗, 欢迎来本镇
What's up? Welcome to town.
来吧,别不好意思
Come on, don't be shy.
胡子很漂亮,象林肯似的
请坐吧,兄弟们
I like that beard. Abe Lincoln-style.
Have a seat, boys.
- Murph!
- Deeds?
-Murph!
-Deeds?
- 你不是病了么?
- 我骗你的,朋友
-I thought you were sick today.
-That was a lie, pal.
你玩我啊?
You fooled me.
- 是么?
- 是的
-I did?
-Yeah.
-  Deeds先生?
-  叫Deeds就行
-Mr. Deeds?
-Just Deeds.
听你电话里的声音好象病的很重,
好小子, 再说一遍听听
You sounded so sick on the phone.
You're good. Do that sick voice again.
Deeds, 我今天喉咙发炎没法上班了
Deeds, I can't come to work today.
I think I got strep throat.
难以置信,你完全可以去演广播剧什么的
That's unbelievable.
You could be a radio actor or something.
- 多谢,朋友
- Sure.
-Thanks, buddy.
-Sure.
Hey, Deeds. 快点读贺卡吧,
我还要回去值勤
Hey, Deeds. Read a card already.
I got to get back on duty.
我得去了,很高兴见到两位
I'd better get up there.
Good meeting you, gentlemen.
Deeds先生, "Preston Blake"这个名字你熟悉吗?
Mr. Deeds, does the name Preston Blake
mean anything to you?
我妈界婚后姓 Blake
Mom's maiden name was Blake.
这星期只读一张,但我预感它会是一个转折点
Only one this week, but I got a feeling
it'll end my losing streak with Hallmark.
Preston Blake 是你母亲的叔叔
Preston Blake was your mother's uncle.
你不是开玩笑吧,我有个叔公?
真意外,他好么?
You're kidding me, I got an uncle?
Awesome. How's he doing?
他死了
He's dead.
噢,真可惜,我有什么能帮忙的....
Oh, no. If there's anything I can do....
Deeds! Deeds!
等等,伙计们
I'll be right with you guys.
Blake死后留给你一大笔遗产
When Mr. Blake died,
he left an enormous fortune.
一共是...
$40 billion. He left it all...
...400亿美圆! 全是你的, Deeds.
...to you, Deeds.
等会儿
Wait a minute.
你刚才说什么? "我还要回去值勤"
你又不是警察!
What are you talking about, you got
to get back on duty? You're not a cop.
没错,警服是我买的
You're right.
I got this down at the costume shop.
扮扮警察有什么大不了的,哈哈!
But it can't hurt to pretend.
不知死活的家伙!
What a wisenheimer!
好吧,各位观众,表演开始
Okay, everybody, it's showtime.
这是一张"结婚50周年卡"
I call this "50th Anniversary Card."
如今那可真的很难得
Which is quite a feat nowadays.
"50年风风雨雨"
"Fifty years have passed by
with laughter and tears
"可曾记得,当年动物园中携手同游
"Do you remember when we went to the zoo
"把酒言欢"
"and that time we drank all the beers"
干杯!
Beers!
"愿多陪你50载"
"I promise to love you for 50 years more
"哪怕老婆变肥婆"
"Even when your bosoms sag down to the floor"
太绝了! 他怎么想出来的?
That was awesome! How's he do it?
你以后不用再送批萨了, Deeds.
It looks like you won't have
to deliver pizza anymore, Deeds.
你现在富可敌国
You're a very rich man.
那和送批萨有什么关系?
What's that got to do with delivering pizzas?
女士们! 上面那盒是你们的
Ladies! The top one is yours.
-谢谢你, Deeds.
-当然
-Thank you, Deeds.
-Of course.
-真好吃!
-Deeds, 有什么新鲜事?
-Yummy!
-So, Deeds, what's new?
我刚知道自己有个叔公,不过他死了
I found out I have an uncle, but he died.
太遗憾了
That's too bad.
-但他留给我400亿美圆
-那是件好事
-He gave me $40 billion, though.
-Well, that's nice.
Oh, 是啊!
Oh, yeah!
别把钱全花在那些录音机上
Don't you go and spend it all
on some fancy record player.
我不会的
I won't.
这些是你朋友, Deeds?
Who are your friends, Deeds?
抱歉,Chuck, Cecil,
她们是Jane, Kitty and Sue.
I'm sorry.
Chuck, Cecil, this is Jane, Kitty and Sue.
-很高兴见到你, Cecil.
-是我的荣幸, Kitty(小猫)
-Pleasure to meet you, Cecil.
-Pleasure's all mine, Kitty.
还是叫你 "喵"
Or should I just say, "Meow"?
别发情了, Anderson.
Keep it in your pants, Anderson.
-这笔钱怎么会由我继承呢?
-你是Blake先生目前最近的亲戚了
-Now, why am I inheriting this money?
-You're Mr. Blake's closest living relative.
- 是吗? 没其他人了么?
- 没有,事实如此
-Really? He had nobody else?
-Nope, that's it.
老天,我甚至没见过他!
Gosh, I never even met the guy.
帮我拿一下好么?
Would you hold this for a second?
Wetherley先生,你好吗?
Mr. Wetherley. How you doing, pal?
很好, Deeds. 正想去一趟药房
Very well, Deeds. Just going to the pharmacy.
好的,我帮你走快两步吧!
Well, let me get you there a little quicker.
- 你太太好么?
- 她很好
-How's your wife?
-She's fine.
- 好极了,替我问候她
- 我会的
-Terrific. Say hi for me.
-I will.
到了
Okay. Here you go.
- 谢谢你背我, Deeds.
- 别客气
-Thanks for the lift, Deeds.
-You got it.
我们想请你去纽约,就几天时间
We need you to come back to New York with us.
Just for a few days.
要请你签几份文件
We're drawing up some papers
you'll need to sign.
什么文件?
What kind of papers?
实际上,你已经继承了Blake媒体公司的
300万股份
Technically, you've inherited
300 million shares of Blake Media, lnc.
Chuck和我, 还有其他股东, 将会用...
Chuck and I, along with
some of the partners, will buy that stock...
...400亿美圆购买你的股份,
为此我们必须到处贷款--
...for $40 billion,
which we've had to borrow from various--
别提那些金融方面的麻烦事了!
Who cares about the financial mumbo jumbo?
我们需要一些时间来玩文字游戏罢了
We need a little time
to dot the t's and cross the i's.
这段时间,我们希望你能够避开新闻界
And while we're doing that,
we need you to stay away from the press.
几星期后,此事会慢慢被遗忘....
The media frenzy will die down
in a couple weeks but until then....
你也不想这个小镇被记者们糟蹋,对吧?
You don't want reporters crawling
all over this lovely little town, do you?
Oh, 当然不!
Oh, no!
- 鬼眼!
- 什么?
-Crazy Eyes!
-What?
你好吗,朋友?
你要的批萨,是你最喜欢的口味
How you doing, pal?
I got your pizza, just the way you like it.
Oh, 太好了!
Oh, yes!
法国风味外加巧克力夹心饼, Deeds.
French fries and Oreos.
You know me all too well, Deeds.
你犯了什么事儿?
What are you in for?
因为袭击邮差,监禁一晚
I'm doing a one-nighter
for biting Ed the mailman.
那家伙想给我下咒, 就象巫师之类
The guy was trying to cast a spell on me,
like a wizard.
- 你肯定?
- 不,或许他只是在招手?
-Are you sure about that?
-I don't know. Maybe he was just waving.
- 他们是谁?
- 这是纽约来的Chuck 和Cecil
-Who are your friends?
-This is Chuck and Cecil from New York.
我不喜欢他们
I don't like them.
好吧,很高兴见到你
Okay. Nice seeing you.
我从没去过纽约,可以去看看风景
I've never been to New York before.
I suppose I could check out the sights.
- 给我一小时准备一下,好么?
- 没问题
-Give me an hour to pack, okay?
-You got it.
我可能是自从Jimmy McNally去过迪斯尼后,
第一个离开本镇的人
I'll be the first guy to leave here since
Jimmy McNally went to Disney World.
过几天再见, 各位!
See you later, everybody!
明天是儿童免费日,别忘了把凳子弄干净
Tomorrow is "Kids Eat For Free" Day.
Don't forget to clean the highchairs.
别担心,我会打理好一切的
Don't worry, I'll take care of everything.
- 去吧,玩个痛快!
- 我会想你的
-Go, have a good time!
-I'll miss you.
再见,Jan. 再见, Murph.
'Bye, Jan. Smell you later, Murph.
- 来张卡片吧!
- 对!
-Give us a card!
-Yeah!
"当我踏上旅途进城去"
"On my way to the big city for a business trip
"从未离开过故乡,一个乡巴佬?
"Never, ever left Mandrake Falls before
Ain't that a pip
"当我离去,会惦记大家"
"But while I'm gone, I know I'll miss you all a lot"
"衣锦还乡时别忘了带上礼物"
"So bring your rich butt back here
and buy us all a shot"
没问题, pal!
You got it, pal!
别乱跑
Take it easy.
发生了本年度最轰动的事件,
但我们竟然一无所获?
The biggest story of the year
and we've got nothing?
你们想去当个小报记者吗? 我不这么看!
Do you people want to be tabloid journalists?
Because I don't think so.
为了新闻,你们必须不择手段
想当初...
You've got to be ruthless. When I started out...
...我躲在雪糕箱子里
...I slept in Tom and Roseanne's dumpster
for two days...
- ...在Tom和Roseanne的垃圾箱里足足呆了两天
- 有消息了!
-...disguised as a giant carton of ice cream.
-I got it!
我在Blake公司的消息人士说
公司的直升机...
My source at Blake says
the company helicopter...
... 今天中午起程飞往Mandrake山谷
...took off from there this afternoon
with two male passengers aboard...
-...有两名乘客
- 去哪儿?
-...headed for Mandrake Falls.
-Where?
新汉普郡的一个乡下小镇
Some little hick-ass town in New Hampshire.
但回来时有三名乘客
But now they're on their way back
with three male passengers.
- 多了一个人!
- 聪明!
-That's one more!
-Duh!
干的好, Marty，第三个乘客就是我们要找的人
That third guy's our heir. Nice work, Marty.
他们本应5点钟到达
They were supposed to arrive
at Blake Media at 5:00.
但他们在康涅狄格临时停留了一阵
But they made an unscheduled stop
in Connecticut.
能吃到这么好的东西真是太棒了！
I'm so happy I got the Big Bacon Classic.
谢谢你们，实在是太美味了
Thanks for stopping. This is unbelievable.
- 乐意效劳
- 觉得味道怎么样, Cecil?
-Happy to do it.
-How's that Frosty treating you, Cecil?
你胡子上沾了点东西，哈哈，骗你的
You got some on your beard. I'm just kidding.
瞧他多有意思！
I got him big time, man.
两小时内节目就要开始
I'm going on the air in two hours' time.
到那时，我要知道他的一切
听见了吗, Jim.
And I want that guy's life story by then.
I'm talking to you, Jim.
还有, Babe. Babe?
And I'm also talking to you, Babe. Babe?
Babe死到哪儿去了?
Where the hell's Babe?
你又没去开会，Mac发火了
You missed another staff meeting. Mac's pissed.
等我把Blake的消息给他，他就会消气的
He won't be pissed when I crack this Blake story.
- 你有什么消息?
- 没有，你呢?
-What do you got?
-Nothing. Do you have anything?
我很快就会有大把消息了
I'll have a lot more in a few hours.
你得帮帮我
You got to be a pal.
我需要这个新闻，
我身无分文，而Mac还要炒了我
I need this story.
I'm flat broke and Mac is going to fire me.
你会身无分文?
这儿就数你赚的最多了！
How're you flat broke?
You make more money than anyone here.
- 你的钱都花哪儿去了?
- 买鞋
-What did you blow it on?
-Shoes.
明天中午我会把消息全告诉你
I'll tell you everything I know
over lunch tomorrow...
...这次别让你那个开CLUB的男朋友...
...as long as your club promoter boyfriend...
...再用摩托车撞我了
...doesn't try to run me over
with his motorcycle again.
别担心，我们最近没怎么来往
You're safe there.
Ken and I are kind of taking a break.
是吗? 你们分手了?
Really? So he moved out?
Babe, 干嘛睡在这儿? 我那儿有空房间
Babe, what are you staying here for?
I have a spare bedroom.
我去过你那儿,记得吗?
We tried that once, remember?
我睡醒时发现, 你喘着粗气站我床边
I woke up and you were standing
over my bed, breathing heavily.
我那是哮喘发作,找不到药
I was having an asthma attack.
I couldn't find my puffer.
嘿,慢点, 伙计们
你们在打饱嗝啊!
Easy, fellows.
The Biggie Fries are making a comeback.
喜欢足球么? 帕特队今年可能夺得联合会杯
You guys football fans? The Pats
could take the conference this year.
海豚队没那么强,至于喷气机队只配掂底
The Dolphins are overrated
and the Jets are choke artists.
如果我是你,我可不会这么说, Deeds先生
I wouldn't say that, Mr. Deeds.
- 叫我Deeds就行. 你说为什么?
- 你是喷气机队的老板, Deeds.
-Just Deeds. Why is that, though?
-You own the Jets, Deeds.
是吗?
I do?
那可真没面子
That sucks.
希望他们可别在总决赛碰上帕特队,
要不然,我宁愿去死好过些
I hope they don't play the Pats in the playoffs
or I'll have to kill myself.
我还是觉得有点担心
I'm still very worried about this.
你不是刚抽完大麻吧?
你担心什么呢!
What do you got in that pipe, hashish?
You're paranoid.
- 这小子简直是上天的恩赐
- 要是他不肯卖股份怎么办?
-This guy's perfect for us.
-What if he won't sell us his shares?
我既然能说服整个公司...
If I got Blake to trust me with his company...
...自然也能摆平这小子!
你看他!
...I can get this moron to do the same.
Look at him.
不错, Anderson.
That's right, Anderson.
够了!
Enough!
真扫兴
Party pooper.
老天爷!
Holy cow!
你好吗, 纽约?
What's up, New York?
我来啦!世界上最棒的城市!
It's an honor to come
to the greatest city in the world!
恭喜你, Deeds, 你现在是全纽约最
有钱的单身汉了!
Congratulations, Deeds, you're now
the most eligible bachelor in New York.
我可不想别人因为我有钱而追求我
I don't want to meet a girl
just because I'm wicked rich.
话虽如此, 但你去我们的俱乐部看看之后
That's nice, but let's see
how you stick to your guns...
或许就不会这么想了
...once you've paid a visit to one
of our many fine gentlemen's clubs.
是吗?
What?
我爸救过我妈的命
My father saved my mother.
她当时滑冰掉进冰窟窿里
She was figure skating and fell through the ice.
我常想,我可能也得这样,够刺激的
I always thought I'd meet
a girl the same way. Bullspit like that.
看来,我要经常帮你留意
那些遇到麻烦的女士才行
Then I'll just keep a lookout
for ladies in distress, as it were.
- 那太好了
- 喂! Mandrake山谷来的 !
-That'd be nice.
-Hey, Mandrake Falls!
保安,抓住他!
Security, stop that guy!
站住! 别跑!
Stop! Come back!
那张照片能值十万块,
而且不用一小时就会满天飞了
He'll get $100,000 for the picture.
It'll be on the news in an hour.
他这套惊险动作也值这个价钱了
He deserves it with those
James Bond moves he just pulled.
不,他该被割断喉咙,无耻的家伙,
来吧,咱们走
No, he deserves to get his throat cut,
the filthy spy. Come on, let's go.
这就是我叔公的家?
So this is where my uncle lived?
是的, 他在这儿住了35年
Yes, sir. For the last 35 years
of his astonishing life.
- 你像是突然冒出来似的
- 我非常非常的敏捷, 先生
-You kind of snuck up on me there.
-I am very, very sneaky, sir.
我见识过了，我叫Deeds.
I see that. My name is Deeds.
我是Emilio, 先生，我是您的仆人
I am Emilio, sir. I am your servant.
仆人？ 我可用不着什么仆人,
交个朋友倒是可以
Servant? I don't want a servant,
but if you want to be my friend, I'll take that.
朋友?
Friends.
没错,好朋友
Yes, good friends.
您想回房间去吗? 今天一定很劳累了吧
Would you like to go down to your apartment?
I'm sure it's been an exhausting day.
- 你的意思呢, Chuck?
- 那里很安全
-That okay with you, Chuck?
-You'll be safe there.
我们可能要花几天时间
来准备文件让你签字
It'll take us a couple days
to draw up the papers for you to sign.
- 在自己家里慢慢享受吧
- 妙极了
-Go make yourself at home.
-Terrific.
- 回头见
- 先生,我们一会儿见
-Later.
-I will be with you shortly, sir.
好的,幸会了,我是Deeds
You got it. Nice to meet you. I'm Deeds.
- 我是Reuben, 先生
- 这电梯真是不错
-I'm Reuben, sir.
-This is a wicked nice elevator.
看好他, Emilio. 否则有你好瞧的
Keep an eye on him, Emilio. Or it's your ass.
见到您我很高兴,先生
It's nice to see you too, sir.
这份工作怎么样, Reuben?
So how's the elevator business
treating you, Reuben?
"有起有落"!
It has its ups and downs.
没错! 没错!
All right! All right!
说的好!
That was good.
好家伙, 你怎么这么快啊?
Jeesum crow, how'd you get down here so fast?
身手敏捷, 先生, 这边走
Sneaky-sneaky, sir. Right this way.
Wow.
怎么了,先生?
Is something the matter, sir?
- 是回声,先生
- 是啊,你试试
-That's an echo, sir.
-Yeah, you try it.
- 我,先生?
- 很有意思的
-Me, sir?
-It's a lot of fun.
来吧,大声点儿
Come on, you can do it louder than that.
- 厉害
- 谢谢你,先生
-Serious.
-Thank you, sir.
嘿,朋友,想不想试试?
Hey, buddy, how you doing?
You want to give it a shot?
不错
Nice.
大家都想试试吗 ? 一起怪叫
You guys want to join us? Make a weird noise.
真有意思, 不过我有点累了,想去睡觉
That was a great time. Well, I'm tired.
I'd like to go to sleep.
- 这边
- 谢谢你们, 大家去睡个好觉
-This way.
-Thank you very much. Good night, everyone.
晚安
Good night.
你是不是打算睡在那儿,直到邮报把新闻全抢走?
You just going to lie there
and let the Post take your story?
你好吗, 纽约?
What's up, New York?
屋里竟然有个饮水器,不错!
He had a water fountain in his room. I love it.
是夏威夷果汁
That's Hawaiian Punch.
他喜欢...
He adored...
...夏威夷果汁
...Hawaiian Punch.
Wow! 又被你吓了一跳!
Wow! You kind of just snuck up on me there.
恐怕您还没适应我的敏捷
I fear you're underestimating the sneakiness, sir.
可能吧,你在那儿干什么?
I guess I was. What are you doing down there?
我帮您换袜子
I am assisting you with your sock change.
帮我换袜子? 不必了,起来吧
You'd change my socks for me?
You don't got to do that. Stand up.
谢谢您
Thank you.
而且,你一定不会想碰我的右脚
Besides, you don't want
to have to touch my right foot.
我当童子军时,右脚严重冻伤,
你瞧
I got wicked bad frostbite when I was
in the Scouts. Check it out.
够恐怖的,是吧?
Pretty messed up, huh?
一想起它,恐怕我这一辈子都会作恶梦
The hideousness of that foot
will haunt my dreams forever.
是的,有人也这么说过
Yeah, I've heard that before.
真正恐怖的是, 这只脚一点感觉都没有!
But the weird thing is I got no feeling left in it.
你就算用力踩,我也不会疼
So you could jump on it and it wouldn't hurt me.
- 来,试试踩两脚
- 还是不必了吧,先生
-Go ahead, jump on it.
-I'd really rather not, sir.
踩吧, 求你了
Please jump on my foot.
没感觉
I didn't feel that.
你就这么大劲儿? 不如去壁炉那儿
把烧火棍拿来, 给我来几下结实的
What else you got? Get that
fireplace poker and whack my foot.
- 一定要这么做吗?
- 多有意思啊,去拿吧
-Do I absolutely have to?
-It's going to be fun. Just grab it.
我的朋友有空时都喜欢这么干
All my friends do this when they're wasted.
来吧
Come on.
来呀, 狠狠来几下
Go ahead, give it a whack.
- 没事儿
- 真的?
-Nothing.
-Really?
恐怖吧?
Isn't that sick?
完全没感觉, 真变态, 接着打
Didn't feel that. Isn't that awesome? Go ahead.
没事儿
Nothing.
开始觉得过瘾了,对吧?
来呀! 别手下留情!
You're starting to like it, aren't you?
Chop that wood!
没错,就是这样!
That's it!
啊！你这个变态的家伙！
你真狠啊!
You're sick! You're sick!
Why would you do that?
我骗你的,朋友
I'm just kidding you, pal.
- 真被你吓着了
- 我看见了,你的样子....
-You had me going there.
-I saw your face, you were like....
我要去问问Cedar和Anderson
今天该干什么呢?
I got to find out from Cedar and Anderson
what I'm supposed to do today.
帮我把它拔出来好么, 我给钉在地上了
So could you take that out of my foot?
I'm nailed to the ground.
行了
There you go.
我必须强调, 这次的会谈请各位保守秘密...
I must insist on absolute secrecy
regarding this discussion...
...直到我正式获得Blake先生的全部股份
...till I've officially acquired Mr. Blake's shares.
如果那些内容可以接受的话,
在我看来...
If that's acceptable,
then as far as I'm concerned...
...2000个电台已经是诸位的了
...you've just bought 2,000 radio stations.
早上好
Good morning.
Deeds.
大家在忙什么?
What's up?
一点生意上的事
Doing a little business.
这间房子也有回音, 你们一定知道
This room's an echo room, too.
I'm sure you guys already knew that.
你有何贵干?
May I help you?
只是来看看今天有什么事可干
I just wanted to see
if there's anything I should do today.
所有的事情都有人负责
I think we've got everything under control.
总有点什么事吧? 在没签文件之前
这里还是属于我的,对吧?
There's got to be something. Until I sign
those papers I own this place, right?
什么?
What?
请各位稍等片刻
Ladies and gentlemen,
pardon me a moment, please.
当然
Of course.
你好吗, 老兄? 我昨晚一直梦见冰天雪地, 你呢?
What's up, buddy? I was dreaming
about Frosties all last night. You?
我也一直在做梦,可是和你的不一样
I tried to make my own at home,
but it wasn't the same.
Deeds.
公司每个股东,无论大小,都有发言权
Every stockholder, large and small,
has a say in the operation of this company.
但那是在每年的股东大会上
They have this say
at the annual stockholders' meeting.
其他的时间, 公司的运作是由行政人员
The other 364 days of the year,
the officers of the company, like me...
- 比如我,来负责管理的
- 你的意思是我不应该插手
-...run the show.
-You mean now that my uncle's gone.
是的,而且这也不是什么有意思的事
Yeah, and it's not all fun and games.
公司有太多的事情要处理...
This company is a player on so many levels
and in so many areas...
...完全是24个小时工作制
...that running it is literally a 24-hour-a-day job.
我昨晚只睡了三个小时
I only got three hours of sleep last night.
那应该是"21个小时工作制",对吧?
Then it's actually a 21-hour-a-day job, huh?
让开,小姐,
我才不管他妈的什么会议!
Move it, lady.
I don't give a damn about no meeting.
Cedar先生, 对不起--
Mr. Cedar, I am sorry--
上个赛季我打了3500码, 现在我不干了
I passed for 3,500 yards last season
and I ain't gonna touch a football...
除非你们这帮有钱的混蛋
同意新的和约
...until you get off your fat, rich asses
and renegotiate my bullshit contract.
伙计,当着女士的面,说话要小心些
Easy with the language, buddy.
There are ladies present.
你闭上嘴,有钱的臭小子!
Shut the hell up, rich boy!
马上给我加工资,否则你们这帮混--
I want more money, or you all can just suck my--
我警告过你的
I warned you.
说真的,你倒下去的样子活象一袋番茄,
来吧
You went down like a sack of potatoes,
I'll tell you that much. Come on.
起来吧,大块头
Come on, big man. Upsy-daisy.
女士们先生们,足球!
Mesdames and Gentlemen, football!
你的合同是怎么回事?
What's the problem with your contract?
我认为如果我打的好,就应该签新的和约,
赚更多的钱!
I figured if I played well,
I'd renegotiate and get more money.
如果你打的不好,
我们能不能重新签约减少你的酬金呢?
If you didn't play well,
could we renegotiate and pay you less?
妈的, 休想!
Shit, no!
我是说, 不行
I mean, no.
这对我可不公平
Doesn't seem fair to me.
- 他是我们的得分手
- 我明白, Chuck. 让我处理吧
-He led the League in touchdown passes.
-That's okay, Chuck. I got this one.
听着,朋友们,我要提高工资...
Listen, fellows, I want more money...
...否则我一场都不打了
...or I ain't even gonna play another down.
好吧, 我们只能请你走人了!
Well, we'll have to let you go then.
-"请我走人"?
- 没错,你被解雇了
-"Let me go"?
-Yeah, you're fired.
那么我可以与其他球队签约了?
So can I sign with another team?
随便你,不过我建议你改变一下态度...
You can do anything.
I suggest you change your attitude...
...否则,没人会愿意和你共事的
...or nobody will want to work with you.
再见
'Bye.
Deeds.
Kevin 两年前得了Heisman奖,
他是我们的顶尖球员
Kevin won the Heisman Trophy two years ago.
He is our best player.
- 别担心,他会回来的
- 你们会后悔的!
-Don't worry, he'll be back.
-Biggest mistake of your lives!
这东西真不错
This thing is cool.
干嘛不出去走走, 去看看纽约,
好东西还多着呢, 带上这个
Why don't you get out and enjoy the city?
Everything's fine here. Take that with you.
还是留在这儿吧, 好吧, 有事尽管叫我
I'll leave it here. That's all right.
But call me if you need me.
- 当然
- 谢谢, 再见 Anderson.
-Absolutely.
-Thanks. Love you, Anderson.
另外, 各位好像是法国人,
[法语]大家好!
All you guys, I noticed you were French.
The opposite of bonjour to you.
你染金发可真性感
You look so hot as a blond.
样子变化不大么？希望没人认得出我
It's not too streaky?
I feel like he did it really streaky.
我喜欢你这个样子，不过还是让我去吧，
可能有危险的
I love it, but let me go undercover.
This could get dangerous.
他喜欢的是落难女子，不是浑身香水味的男人
He said he likes ladies in distress,
not men who wear too much cologne.
- 他来了
- 谢谢你带我出来
-There he is.
-Thanks for the tour.
- 别客气
- 快打开摄像机,动手吧
-You're welcome.
-Hidden cameras on, ready? Molest me.
- 快点啊,你得袭击我!
- 好吧!
-Molest me!
-You got it!
- 天哪,救命!
- 来吧
-God, help!
-Give it to me.
- 救命,抢劫啊!
- 好啊!
-Help, I'm being mugged!
-All right!
救命! 救命! 打劫啊!
Help! Help! I'm being mugged!
- 够了!
- 祝你好运,回头办公室见
-Stop it!
-Good luck. See you at the office.
- 别担心,我会抓住他的
- 噢,老天!
-Don't worry, I'll get him.
-Oh, shit!
站住
Stop right there.
给我趴下!
Come on!
兄弟,你是怎么搞的?
What's your problem, pal?
起来
Come up here.
小姐,手袋帮你拿回来了,
老兄,找份正经工作吧
Got your pocketbook. Get a job, pal.
小姐! 小姐!
Miss! Miss!
- 你没事吧?
- 怎么回事?
-Are you okay?
-What happened?
我扶你起来
Let me help you up.
没事了,没事了
All right, now. All right.
小姐你刚刚被纽约歹徒袭击
Ma'am, you were just the victim
of a New York City mugger.
我猜,那只不过是个小毛贼罢了
As I suspected, he was a coward and a weakling.
竟然还满身香水味
And also wore more cologne
than any man should wear.
- 我帮你把提包拿回来了
- 谢谢
-I got this back for you, though.
-Thank you.
- 要不要送你去医院?
- 不,不必了
-Can I take you to the hospital?
-No, no.
我没事儿,只是有些头晕和受惊过度
I'll be all right.
I just feel a little dizzy and violated.
我没事的
I'm fine.
别这样,你还是去医院看看吧
Please, let me take you to the emergency room.
我真的没事,我只是...
I'm sure I'll be all right. I just need to...
...或者走走就行了....
...perhaps walk it off or....
- 能扶我一下么?
- 没问题
-Could you?
-Sure.
谢谢你
Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
我叫Pam. Pam Dawson.
My name is Pam. Pam Dawson.
我叫Deeds. 我不是本地人,来这儿旅游
My name is Deeds. I'm not from here.
I'm just visiting.
你从哪来?
Where do you hail from?
Mandrake山谷, 一个没多少人知道的小镇
在新安普郡
Mandrake Falls, New Hampshire.
Just a little town nobody's ever heard of.
我也是从小镇来的
I'm from a little town like that.
- 在爱荷华
- 是吗? 在哪儿?
-In lowa.
-Is that right? What part?
Winchestertonfieldville
Winchestertonfieldville.
爱荷华州Winchestertonfieldville,一个小镇
Yes, the small town
of Winchestertonfieldville, lowa.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 你来纽约干什么?
- 我在学校当护士
-What are you doing in New York?
-I'm a school nurse.
- 你不可能是护士
- 为什么,你不相信吗?
-There's no way you're a school nurse.
-Why, don't you believe me?
你这么好心,怎么可能是护士
You're too nice to be a school nurse.
我学校的护士可恶极了,
每次我告诉她我胃疼...
My school nurse was so mean,
every time I'd tell her I had a tummy ache...
...她都会把我赶回教室,
命令我"不许哭哭啼啼"的!
...she'd send me back to my class
and say, "Stop whining."
- 真是太可怕了!
- 是啊,我天天都这么说!
-But that's awful!
-Well, I said it every day.
我很想念自己的妈妈
I missed my mother.
多可爱!
That's sweet.
Dawson小姐?
Miss Dawson?
我在想,你是否愿意与我...
How would you like to maybe go out...
...共进一个纽约式的晚餐?
...and have a New York City dinner with me?
天哪！
Golly.
听起来很不错
That sounds wonderful.
- 是吗?
- 是的
-It does?
-Yeah.
- 那咱们去吧
- 好吧
-Let's do it, then.
-Okay.
去死吧，混蛋
Damn you, Old Spice.
这么说你自己开了间批萨店，还喜欢写诗
So you run this pizza place
and you have your poetry.
你来这儿只是为旅游?
What brings you to the big city?
事实上，我刚刚继承了400亿美元遗产
Actually, I just inherited $40 billion.
那可真不少, 但我总觉得那么大一笔钱
多少有些来路不正
Well, that's nice, but I think anything
over $30 billion is just gravy.
有道理
I like that.
你的金发真漂亮
Your hair is very blond and pretty.
我有瑞典学童
I'm of Swedish ancestry.
- 是吗?
- 是
-Really?
-Yes.
我祖父住在ABBA.
My grandfather was in ABBA.
ABBA乐队?
ABBA, the band?
劳驾, 有没有什么名人来这儿?
Excuse me,
do you get any famous people in here?
什么大人物都有
Famous, rich, powerful.
是吗? 我们那儿可没什么名人
Really? We don't get
any famous people in Mandrake Falls.
有一次,史蒂芬.金 路过我们的加油站...
Stephen King stopped by
our gas station one time...
...但是竟然没人敢和他搭话
...but everyone was too scared to talk to him.
我想他一定很可怕
I'd imagine he'd be very spooky.
加油站的员工Jake, 和他对望过一眼
Jake, the gas station attendant,
made eye contact with him.
当晚体重就掉了200磅
That night he lost 200 pounds.
Wow.
你们的奶酪烤鸡很快就好了
Your chicken parmesan should be ready soon.
好的,伙计 , 我看到
那边有一对夫妇在庆祝结婚周年
Okay, buddy. I saw a couple over there.
It's their anniversary.
把这个给他们,但别说是我们给的
Give them this. Don't say it's from us, though.
这差不多有2万快呢!
This is like $20,000.
就跟他们说,是餐厅酬宾活动之类的
谢了,伙计
Tell them it was a restaurant giveaway
or something. Thanks, buddy.
这可是个花钱的好办法
That's an awfully nice way
to start spending your money.
- 我不会认错人吧?
- 谁?
-Is that who I think it is?
-Who?
Preston Blake的侄子, 身价400亿的那个
Preston Blake's nephew, the $40-billion man.
我们得会会他, Dave?
We have to meet him. Dave?
是吗, 那个歹徒没什么事儿就好
Gosh, I hope that mugger got home okay.
- Deeds先生
- 什么事?
-Mr. Deeds.
-Yeah.
Simonds先生想请您赏脸过去坐坐!
Mr. Simonds would like
to invite you to join his party.
为什么?
Why is that?
因为大家想一睹您女朋友的风采
Just to enjoy the pleasure of your company.
是吗, 他可真有眼光
Wow, that's pretty cool of him.
真是个热情的拥抱, Deeds.
That was a very nice hug, Deeds.
非常感谢你的邀请, 我们非常高兴
It's wicked nice of you to invite us over.
This is awesome.
- 我们在哪儿见过面吗?
- 我想没有,除非你的孩子生过病
-Have we met?
-Not unless you have a sick kid.
您现在是城里的大人物了,Deeds先生
You're a very important man
in this town now, Mr. Deeds.
这我可不知道
I don't know about that.
我在Metropolitan歌剧院工作...
I sing at the Metropolitan Opera...
...我们百分之五十以上的经费
是由Blake媒体公司提供的
...and Blake Media contributes
50 percent of our budget.
因此,我代表歌剧院:
So, on behalf of the opera:
"感-谢-你"
"Thank you"
唱得真好!
That was awesome!
不过你该感谢我叔公,而不是我
You shouldn't thank me, though.
You should thank my great-uncle.
他是个有趣的人
He was an interesting man.
我和他在古根海姆委员会共事过
I served on the board
of the Guggenheim with him.
是吗? 我可没听说过那个地方,
不过祝它好运
Really? I'm not sure what that is,
but good luck with it.
我很乐意为你在"纽约人"写篇文章
I'd love to write a piece on you
for The New Yorker.
"纽约人"是什么?
What's The New Yorker?
是一份杂志
It's a magazine.
发表一些短评和讽刺漫画
With essays, witty cartoons.
我经常看Mandrake的小报,
他们也登很多漫画
I read the Mandrake Falls Gazette
and they got some cartoons in there also.
知道最有意思的是谁吗, 那个叫贝利的家伙
You know who's a riot? That Beetle Bailey guy.
整天戴着顶帽子,到处惹事
He's always wearing his hat and doing his thing.
很荣幸见到了一位真正的作家, George.
But it is an honor to meet
a real writer like you, George.
我一直也想发表点东西...
I've been trying
to get my stuff published for years...
... 但Hallmark的门槛实在太高了
...but Hallmark is one tough cookie to crack.
- Hallmark?
- 他喜欢写贺卡
-Hallmark?
-He writes greeting cards.
- 试试而已
- 您一定要让我们见识一下
-I try.
-You must share one with us.
- 我喜欢你的口音, "法国先生"
- 谁是"法国先生"?
-I don't know about that, Mr. French.
-Who's Mr. French?
- 他象不像那个"法国先生"?
- 完全没听说过
-Doesn't he look like Mr. French?
-I've never heard of him.
来嘛
Come on.
好吧,就读一个吧
All right, I'll give you one.
这是我最近在写的一张母亲节贺卡
This is a Mother's Day card I've been working on.
"老妈, 是你带我来到这个星球"
"Mom, you are the one
who brought me to planet Earth
"生我时你痛苦了14个钟头"
"You are the one who suffered
through my 14-hour birth
"每次玩耍后,您把汽水送到我手中"
"You are the one who made lemonade for me
after I'd come back from play
"我爱你,妈,愿您母亲节乐也融融"
"I love you, Mom,
so have a wicked nice Mother's Day"
就是这样了
Something like that.
- 了不起的即兴创作!
-"天才,天才,天才"
-An instant classic!
-"Genius, genius, genius"
你平时是用蜡笔写诗的吧?
Do you write your poems with a crayon?
有意思!
It's amazing!
我知道你们为什么请我们过来了,
想拿我寻开心,对吧?
I see why you brought me here.
To goof on me, huh?
- 别当真, Deeds.
- 闭嘴, George.
-Don't be silly, Deeds.
-Pipe down, George.
对你们来说,我也许很可笑,
但如果你们到Mandrake去...
I may seem funny to you,
but if you came to Mandrake Falls...
...可笑的会是你们,
但是却没人会嘲笑你们...
...you might seem funny to us.
Only nobody would laugh at you...
...令你们尴尬,
因为那不是待客之道!
...and make you feel stupid,
that wouldn't be good manners.
也许我写的东西不怎么样,
但有些人很喜欢
Maybe my poems aren't that great,
but I know some people who like them.
不管怎么说,我尽力了,
我们要走了
Anyways, it's the best I can do.
We're going to get going.
对不起,Pam.
希望你别在意!
Sorry about that, Pam.
I hope I didn't embarrass you.
要不是Dawson 小姐在这儿,
我会好好收拾你们的
And if it wasn't for Miss Dawson being here,
I'd knock your heads in.
我不介意
I don't mind.
那好吧
Okay.
"不"
"No"
我好像拉裤子了
I think I just shat myself.
咱们去哪儿看风景?
How would you like to see the sights now?
我先去补一补妆
I just need to powder my nose.
好的,我帮你拿外套
That would be great. I'll get your coat.
伙计们,这两万块算是赔偿你们的损失,
非常抱歉!
Hey, buddy, this will pay for everything
I damaged. Sorry about that.
- 幸会了,各位
- 谢谢
-Good to meet you guys.
-Thank you.
上帝, 千载难逢的机会
God, that was good stuff.
Mac,我要加薪
I want a raise, Mac.
喂,兄弟,你好吗?
Hey, man! What's up?
老天爷啊, 你是John McEnroe(前网球明星)!
Holy cannoli, you're John McEnroe!
我看见你收拾那帮无礼的家伙,干得好!
I saw what you did to those guys
making fun of you. Nice work.
有时候真是忍无可忍, 你明白的,对吧
Johnny Mac?
You know what it's like to get riled up
don't you, Johnny Mac?
- 我明白
- 我叫Deeds
-That I do.
-I'm Deeds, by the way.
Deeds, 幸会了
去和我喝两杯吧
Deeds, nice to meet you.
You got to let me buy you a drink.
Dawson小姐, 这位是John McEnroe.
Miss Dawson, this is John McEnroe.
- Dawson小姐, 很高兴见到你
- 我也是
-Miss Dawson, nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you, too.
我答应陪Dawson小姐去观光
I promised Miss Dawson I'd take her sightseeing.
这里风景不错,我很喜欢
The sights are great.
I've seen the sights. I love the sights.
我带你们看看纽约不为人知的一面
Let me show you a New York
most people will never see.
- 你认为怎么样, Dawson小姐?
- 听起来挺有意思的!
-That okay with you, Miss Dawson?
-Sounds like fun!
为狂欢之夜干杯!
Here's to a big night on the town.
发生什么事?
What happened?
吃几片阿司匹林吧, Deeds先生
就不会那么头疼了
Here are some aspirins, Mr. Deeds.
They make your head seem smaller.
- 我怎么换上睡衣了?
- 我帮您换的
-How did I get in these pajamas?
-I changed you.
我很小心的,先生
I was very gentle, sir.
我猜,全曼哈顿的酒昨晚都让我喝光了!
I think I drank all the alcohol in Manhattan
last night.
Dawson小姐也是这么说的
And you nearly succeeded,
according to Miss Dawson.
Dawson小姐! 我记得好像没送她回家, 她好吗?
Miss Dawson! I don't even remember
taking her home. Is she okay?
我自己拿主意,用公司的车送她回去了
I took the liberty of sending her off
in the company limousine.
她遇到麻烦,我帮了她
She was a lady in distress and I helped her.
昨晚,我梦见她了
Dreamt about her last night.
通常, 喝醉的人是不会做梦的
Usually, when you get blackout drunk
you don't dream.
书上说的
So I read.
什么事儿, Chuck?
What's up, Chuck?
美国最新的亿万富翁...
America's newest billionaire...
-...愚蠢的酒鬼
- 这是什么?
-...stupid and drunk.
-What's this?
昨晚, Longfellow Deeds一定很尽兴
It was quite a night for Longfellow Deeds.
他们现在知道我叫Longfellow了
They'll know my name is Longfellow.
殴打完几位社会名流之后...
After punching out some society types...
Deeds 又和"网球坏孩子" -- John McEnroe
混到了一块儿!
...Deeds joined forces with the original
bad boy of tennis, John McEnroe.
多么愚蠢的行径!
And stupidity won in straight sets.
他们是怎么拍到的?
How'd they get that footage?
小心,Johnny!
Watch out, Johnny!
你怎么开车的!
不知羞耻的家伙!
What kind of driving is that?
You're a fucking disgrace!
不,先生. 你才不知羞耻!
No, sir. You're a disgrace.
- 太过瘾了, 兄弟!
- Johnny McEnroe!
-We did it, man!
-Johnny McEnroe!
瞧啊, Deeds和McEnroe在一起!
太厉害了!
Look at Deedsy hanging out with McEnroe!
That's awesome!
是啊，我也很喜欢"沙滩小子"
I love the Beach Boys.
Here I go, here I go.
你这种表现可不是我们现在所需要的
This is not the kind of attention
we need right now.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
目前来说,你是我们最大的股东...
For the moment you're the largest stockholder...
...你的这种行为...
...and people might think
any instability you show...
...将会直接影响公司的稳定
...may equal instability in the company.
是我的错
My bad.
是我的错,是我的错
My bad. My bad.
好了,好了
Okay. Okay.
- 是我的错
- 没事的
-My bad.
-Okay.
需要我帮您叫车去葬礼吗 ? Cedar先生
Shall I call your car, Mr. Cedar,
to take you to the funeral?
什么葬礼?
What funeral?
你叔公的
Your great-uncle's funeral.
- 是今天?
- 是的
-His funeral's today?
-Today, yes.
我去穿衣服
I'll go get my suit on.
- 听着,多嘴的东西
- 先生?
-Cute, bigmouth.
-Sir?
那个白痴一回到乡下...
As soon as that moron goes back
to Cowpie Falls...
你这个波多黎各笨蛋也给我滚！
...you are out of here
on your fat Puerto Rican ass.
我来自西班牙,先生
I hail from Spain, sir.
Ol?
"此刻, Preston弟兄必在天际飞翔"
Now, Brother Preston is soaring
with eagles high above.
"只因,一生爱心不停释放"
Because he lived a life of love.
"他如今高高在上..."
Yes, he's flying way up high...
"...无人会将他遗忘"
...because he was a supercool guy.
"伟大的生命匆匆逝去..."
He's gone away, too soon, it seems...
"未完的事业何人承继"
...leaving behind his unfinished dreams.
这位老兄写贺卡肯定能发大财!
This guy could make a fortune
writing greeting cards.
"我们的朋友Preston Blake..."
Yes, we remember Preston Blake...
信念坚定,无人能移!
...a man with faith no man could shake.
胆识超群,无人能敌!
A strength no man could break.
品格优良,无人能比!
A character no man could fake.
上帝保佑,愿他安息!
For goodness sake, let's eat some cake.
阿门
Amen.
请留步, 牧师, 您说的太精彩了
Excuse me, Reverend, that was a grand slam.
"在天际翱翔"那段简直太感人了
That part with soaring with the eagles
gave me goosebumps.
- 谢谢你,兄弟
- 我生日那天,朋友们送了个啤酒杯给我
-Thank you, my brother.
-My friend got me a mug for my birthday.
上面写着 "未能展翅高飞,只因鹤立鸡群"
It says, "It's hard to soar with the eagles
when you're surrounded by turkeys."
但还是你的诗更好
But what you said was better.
都很好
It's all good.
安息吧, Preston.
让我们结束今天的仪式
Rest in peace, Preston.
That concludes today's service.
我还想说两句
I actually thought I would say something.
Deeds的口才是学校里最好的
Deedsy was always the best speaker in school.
Deeds?
Deedsy?
只是顺便说几句,阁下
That's some job, by the way, Your Majesty.
我们不是在看"史酷比"吗 ?
I thought we were watching Scooby-Doo.
Hi, 我是 Deeds.
Preston Blake是我的叔公
Hi, my name is Deeds.
I was Preston Blake's great-nephew.
在来这儿的路上, 我做了一首诗献给他
I wrote a poem for him
on my way over here, in my head.
请允许我为大家朗诵
And I'm going to recite it for you.
当然,它和Sharpton牧师的大作无法相比
I didn't realize I'd be following
the rhyme-master Reverend Sharpton.
但我还是想和大家分享
But here we go anyways.
"你攀登高山,建造大楼"
"You climbed mountains and built skyscrapers
"创办报纸,还有精彩的TV-SHOW"
"You made TV shows and put out newspapers
"摆弄股票,你最拿手"
"You were wicked good at doing stocks
"你喜欢,有仆人侍侯左右"
"You liked it
when Emilio would change your socks
"可惜未能与你相处, 哪怕一分一秒"
"We never hung out and that makes me sad
"不然,日子该有多美好"
"AII the good times we could've had"
不错,很压韵
Nice rhyme.
"我去世时,您不该把泪掉"
"But when I die, Uncle Preston,
you'd better say, 'Cheers!'
"因为你我在天堂相会"
"'Cause me and you are hanging
at the pearly gates
"多么美妙,多么美妙!"
"I'll bring the beers, I'll bring the beers"
写得不错!
He's good.
Amen.
或许是你们的习俗,但在我们那儿
I know this is supposed to be
a closed casket, but where I come from...
...一般会打开棺材,以便大家能看见遗体,
追思凭吊...
...we feel it's good to see the body
for the grieving process, so....
抱歉各位,我看还是盖上吧!
Sorry about that! I'll keep this sucker closed.
他还冻得硬邦邦的
He's still pretty frozen.
差不多了
Almost there.
我会帮你照料公司的, 我爱你
I'll keep an eye on the company for you.
Love you.
很高兴见到你,多谢你的大房子
Nice meeting you. Thanks for the apartment.
真疯狂
That was freaky.
各位走好!
Everybody drive home safe.
嘿! 这家伙真是古怪
Man, this guy is in way over his head.
- 你自己小心点
- 今晚约了他 ?
-Take care.
-You'll see him tonight?
是的,我4点钟给他打电话,
然后就准备开工
Yes, I'm calling around 4:00.
That's when I get off work.
别忘了, 我是Pam Dawson, 纯洁的少女,
来自Winchestertonfieldville的护士小姐
Remember, I'm Pam Dawson, virgin school nurse
from Winchestertonfieldville, lowa.
真有你的!
That's priceless.
你,纯洁? 哈哈哈 !
You, a virgin.
- 好的,谢谢你
- 先生,你这是 ?
-All right, thank you.
-Excuse me, sir.
- 是我让他拿的
- 多谢了,Deeds.
-I told him he could have that.
-Thanks.
别客气,伙计. 幸会了
Right on. Nice seeing you.
随时欢迎你来用洗手间,知道吗?
You need to use our bathroom,
come back and use it, okay?
- 好的,Deeds.!
-Will do!
-All right.
今天葬礼上我的表现怎么样?
How do you think I did at the funeral today?
你的话很感人,先生
You spoke beautifully, sir.
我还是有些过意不去
I still feel bad.
我把叔公的胳膊给掰断了
I snapped my uncle's hand off
when I put him back in the casket.
还好,他已经死了, 先生.
Lucky for him, he was dead, sir.
很奇怪,即使他的脸冻成那个样子...
Even though his face was frozen that way...
...可我觉得他还是很快乐,对不对?
...it looked to me like he was a happy guy.
Am I right?
- 他是这样的
- 来,陪我坐坐
-He truly was.
-Come on, sit down, please.
他天天都是这样...
And I got to hang out with him, just like this...
...我们相处了差不多30年
...almost every day for 30 years.
你们都聊些什么话题?
What did you guys talk about?
人生,爱情,艺术,生意之类的
We spoke of life, love, art, wine, business.
他令我获益良多
I learned much from him.
- 你一定很怀念他
- 是的
-I bet you miss him, too.
-I do.
他就像我父亲一样
He was like a parent to me.
你知道的,我没见过自己的父亲,而母亲...
You see, I never knew my father, and Mama...
我刚出生她就去世了
...she passed while giving the birth to me.
- 想来点可可豆么?
- 不了,谢谢
-You want some Cocoa Pebbles?
-No, thanks.
我还有很多活要干
I have much work to do.
- 谢谢你,不用了
- 慢慢吃
-Thanks. You don't have to do that.
-Enjoy your Pebbles.
还有一件事
One more thing.
你叔公也没让我给它换袜子
Your great-uncle did not let me
change his socks for him, either.
我喜欢脚
I like feet.
不知为什么!
I do not know why.
喂?
Hello.
你好,是Deeds么? 我是Pam, Pam Dawson.
Hi, Deeds? It's Pam. Pam Dawson.
你能来电话太好了! 昨晚的事我非常抱歉
I'm so happy you called.
I'm wicked sorry about last night.
我不常喝酒
I don't drink very often.
你酒量不错嘛
I thought you held your liquor very well.
可惜还是吐了你一身!
Unfortunately, I couldn't hold it for too long.
别在意,反正那条裙子我也不是太喜欢
That's okay. I didn't really like that skirt anyway.
又有一个电话进来,
能麻烦你等一等吗?
I'm getting a call on the other line.
Can you hang on for a second?
- 没问题
- 谢谢
-Sure.
-Thank you.
喂
Hello.
Deeds先生, 我是Kevin Ward,
就是上次你揍的那个四分卫
Mr. Deeds, this is Kevin Ward,
the quarterback you punched.
噢,我想起来了,什么事儿,朋友?
What's up, buddy?
我反覆考虑过了,我不该那样目中无人,
I wanted to say that I was thinking it over
and I'd like to live up to my word.
我希望能帮您赢得超级杯
And I'd like to win you a Super Bowl.
- 那太好了,伙计
- 我爸想和您说两句
-That's terrific, pal.
-And my daddy wants to speak to you.
Deeds. 我是Buddy Ward, Kevin的父亲
Deeds. Buddy Ward here, Kevin's daddy.
你好吗, Ward先生?
How you doing, Mr. Ward?
我想感谢你给我儿子上了一课
I just want to thank you
for teaching my boy a lesson.
他是个好孩子,只是
在女士面前说话时要文明一些
He's a good kid. He just has to watch
his language in front of ladies.
我会提醒Kevin,是谁生他出来的
I'll remind Kevin where he comes from.
那太好了
That sounds terrific.
你在女士面前说脏话?
You used foul language in front of a lady?
别打我,爸,别打我!
No, Daddy, no!
Pam
Pam.
我听着呢
Still here.
你在干什么呢,上班?
How's it going? You at work?
- 是的, 我现在在医疗室
- 有"顾客"吗?
-Yep, here in the nurse's office.
-Any customers?
顾客? 噢,你是说生病的孩子
Customers? Oh, sick kids.
恩, 小Billy在这儿
Well, little Billy Barty's here.
- 你哪儿不舒服, Billy?
- Dawson小姐, 我肚子疼
-You're not feeling too good, Billy?
-Miss Dawson, my tummy hurts.
你可以试试安静的躺一会儿
Why don't you just lay back and relax?
你干得不错
That was nice. Good job.
我拉屎屎了
I've got too much doo-doo in my underpants.
臭死了
Make the stinky go away.
看来你要忙一阵子了...
Well, you sound like
you got your hands full, so...
...我还是直说了吧
...I'll just come out with it.
我今晚想约你出来,你愿意吗?
How would you like
to do something with me tonight?
我很愿意
I'd love to do something with you.
太好了
Great.
不过不能去喝酒, 免得给公司惹麻烦
We can't go out drinking.
I got our company in trouble.
好的, 从小家里人就教育我不要喝酒
That's okay.
I was brought up never to drink alcohol.
连酒心糖也别吃
Not even rum raisin ice cream.
没错, 咱们去干点别的吧
I like that. I'll think of something good.
今晚见
See you tonight.
好的,再见
Okay. 'Bye.
我得试试这个
I got to try this.
有意思吧?
Was that awesome?
上垒还是出局?
Am I out or safe?
明白!
I'm with you.
这是什么? 我叔公的日记!
What is this? My great-uncle's personal journal.
- 我能看么?
- 自家人
-Should I read it?
-Family.
没错,自家人,没问题
Family, safe, good.
好吧,晚安! 我后背疼死了!
All right, have a good night. My back hurts!
- 很高兴和你们交易
- 谢谢你,Deeds先生
-Nice doing business with you.
-Thank you.
谢谢你们的自行车
Thanks for the bikes.
这两万块你打算怎么花?
What are you gonna do with your $20,000?
买冰激凌.
你呢?
Buy a giraffe.
What are you gonna do with your $20,000?
退学
Quit school.
好主意,傻瓜才去上学,你们看看我!
Good idea, school is for fools. Look at me!
这公园真美
The park is beautiful.
这些树有没有让你想起Winchestertonfieldville?
These trees, they remind you
of Winchestertonfieldville at all?
是啊,当然,我想起了很多
Oh, yes. Very much so.
在那里的生活很有意思吧?
What was it like growing up there?
非常有意思
It was great.
我还记得那时到街角的杂货铺...
I remember walking down
to the corner drugstore...
...买麦芽糖奶昔
...and getting malted milkshakes.
你家的房子什么样?
What was your house like?
很大,维多利亚式的
We had this big Victorian.
在大街的右边
Right off Main Street.
- 蓝色的百叶窗, 大门是红色的
- 真不错
-Blue shutters and a big red door.
-All right.
- 屋前的院子里有一架秋千
- 太可爱了
-And a tire swing in the front yard.
-I love it.
记得那次我从老Radley的苹果树上摔下来...
And I remember the time I fell out of
old Boo Radley's apple tree...
...把胳膊给摔断了
...and broke my arm.
我父亲, 那时他还没有...
And my father, before he passed away...
死于麻风病
...from the disease of the lepers...
...他抱起我,一直跑到Pepper大夫家
...he came and he scooped me up
and he ran me all the way to Dr. Pepper's.
Pepper大夫
Dr. Pepper.
是的
Yeah.
还好有他
I'm glad that guy was around.
- 想坐一会儿吗?
- 好的
-Want to sit down?
-Sure.
- 谢谢你
- 乐意效劳
-Thank you.
-My pleasure.
在来的路上,我一直在读叔公的日记
I was reading my great-uncle's journal
on my way over to you.
他9岁时写道...
And, when he was age 9...
他们是唯一有收音机的家庭...
...he wrote that he had the only family
on the block with a radio...
...他梦想将来能成为一名DJ(音乐主持人)
...and he was dreaming
of becoming a disc jockey someday.
DJ?
A disc jockey?
知道吗,我小时候一直梦想能成为记者
You know, when I was a kid,
I wanted to be a news reporter.
经常到处去采访别人...
I used to go around interviewing everyone...
...然后在自己的小本子上写呀、写呀
...and writing notes
in my little Holly Hobby notebook.
弄得别人很讨厌，结果捱了不少揍
People didn't like that. I got beat up a lot.
- 还记得打你的家伙吗?
- 忘了,那是很久以前了
-Do you remember their names?
-No, it was a long time ago.
但我奶奶却对我说:
But my grandma said to me:
"总有一天你会成为大记者...
"One day you'll grow up
and work for 60 Minutes...
"...改变这个世界"
"...and make a difference in the world."
你每天都在改变着这个世界, 你是孩子们的好护士
You do make a difference in the world,
every day. You're a school nurse.
对了,还有一件事是关于我叔公的
Anyways, this is what happened to my uncle.
在他晚年那段日子, 他会每天早上3点钟...
Later on in his life, he'd go
to this radio station that he owned...
到自己的电台, 做一个小时的DJ
...at 3:00 in the morning and DJ for an hour.
太有意思了
That's great.
所以,别放弃自己的愿望,
你会成为记者的
So, don't give up hope.
You'll be a reporter someday.
只要你不放弃
If you really want to.
是那样就好了
That would be nice.
- 不好,着火了!
- 着火?
-Jeesum Crow, a fire!
-A fire?
- 我们得去帮忙
- 我们?
-We should help.
-We should?
- 咱们走
- 去着火那里?
-Let's get going.
-To the fire?
- Fifi, 到这儿来
- 跳啊,我们会接住你的
-Fifi, get over here right now.
-Come on, we'll catch you.
走开, 我不能丢下我的小猫,
它们是我唯一的亲人
Go away! I can't leave without my kitties.
They're all I got.
她发疯了!
Crazy lady!
- 噢,小乖乖,你们在哪儿?
- 上去,快!
-Oh, babies, where are you?
-Up there now, get going!
我是Longfellow Deeds, Mandrake镇的
义务消防局长. 我这就上去!
Longfellow Deeds, Mandrake Falls
volunteer fire chief. I'll be up there in a jiff.
- 他发疯了
- 竟然要上去!
-He's crazy.
-He's going up there right now, though.
- 小心,伙计!
- 他要干什么?
-Look at him.
-Where's he going?
瞧啊!
Watch it, man!
- Sully, 那个家伙是谁?
- 我不知道
-Sully, who's that guy up there?
-I don't know.
他说他是Mandrake消防局的
He says he's from
the Mandrake Falls Fire Department.
- 老天,这是什么功夫啊?
- 简直是人猿泰山的亲戚
-How's he climb like that?
-He must have monkey blood in him.
和纽约最勇敢的人并肩战斗
是我的荣幸!
It's an honor to work
with New York's bravest guys.
小心!
Be careful!
- 我来救你了
- 小乖乖,你们在哪啊?
-I'll get you.
-Babies, where are you?
- 女士!
- 老天,太热了
-Ma'am!
-Lord, it's hot in here.
- 小猫咪,到妈妈这儿来
- 请别慌,会没事儿的
-Kitties, come to Mommy.
-Calm down. Everything will be all right.
好吧, 但我决不会丢下我的猫
Okay, but I'm not leaving without my kitties.
- 一共几只?
- 7只.
-How many do you got?
-Seven.
真他妈的多, 快开始找吧!
Holy shit! Let's get cracking.
- 抱歉说粗话
- 接受你的道歉
-I apologize for the language.
-Apology accepted.
- 火灾让我兴奋
- 别客气,尽情享受!
-Fire excites me.
-Knock yourself out.
- 过来
- 那个是Freddy.
-Come here.
-That's Freddy.
- 下去吧!
- 不,我的孩子!
-Here we go!
-Oh, my children!
- 接的好, Pam!
- 你扔的也不错, Deeds!
-Nice catch, Pam!
-Good throw, Deeds!
- 那是Frobo. 谢谢你
- 来了,伙计们
-That's Frobo. Thank you, darling.
-Coming at you, boys.
让我来!
I'll take that.
- 还有几只呢
- Okay, okay.
-There's a lot more.
-Okay, okay.
老天爷, 一只猫!
Holy shit, it's a cat!
好一个长传. 我来了,猫咪
Full snap. I got you, kitty.
接的漂亮!
Nice grab!
还有一只
One more to go.
Fifi, 你在哪儿?
Fifi, where are you?
- 我找到Fifi了
- Oh, 太好了!
-I think I found Fifi.
-Oh, good!
坚持住,小兄弟!
Hang in there, buddy!
我来,我来!
I got it!
来吧,咱们一起跳
Okay, let's do this together.
小心啊!
Be careful!
别担心,这对他们是小菜一碟
All right, they do it all the time. Here we go.
Oh,天哪!
Oh, shit!
Deeds.
我没事
I'm okay.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
是的,太谢谢你了!
Yes, I am. Thanks to you!
救命啊!
You're hurting me!
Longfellow Deeds又在生事了
Longfellow Deeds is at it again.
Coretta Keeling女士成了他受害者...
His latest victim, Coretta Keeling...
...她非常爱自己的小猫咪
...whose only crime
was loving her cats too much.
不幸,被Deeds知道了
And letting Deeds find out about it.
- 我来了!
- 走开!
-I'll get you!
-Go away!
- 真绝了
- 两个一起来!
-I love it.
-Here comes two!
- 杀害猫咪的凶手!
- 害死了可爱的猫咪之后...
-Cat killer!
-After he finished with her cats...
...他又把手伸向了Keeling小姐
...he turned his sights on Miss Keeling herself.
上帝!
My God!
我拍的不是这样
That's not what I shot.
这位Longfellow受到任何惩罚了吗? 没有!
当然不会!
Has Longfellow Deeds been locked up?
Of course not.
我们所遵守的法律在这些公子哥儿眼中,
只是一个玩笑罢了
While the rest of us obey the law,
rich playboys like himself get to laugh at it.
这就是Longfellow Deeds---本周最愚蠢的傻瓜
Longfellow Deeds. Our jackass of the week.
到底是谁? 是谁编辑了带子
What the hell? Who edited that?
是我, 你做的那个版本非常好,
但我需要更夸张一点
I did. Your first cut was great,
but I needed to spice it up a bit.
事实上那是一个多好的素材啊!
The truth was a great story.
他救了那个女人和她的7只小猫
He saved that woman and her seven cats.
- 他是个英雄!
- 英雄是不错
-He was heroic!
-Heroic is nice.
- 但堕落和疯狂更有观众
-Depraved and insane is better.
-Hell, yeah!
这片子是你拍的,干得好,
继续努力!
This footage you're getting, gorgeous.
Keep it coming!
天哪,我们怎么能这样对一个好人?
God, how can we do this to such a sweet guy?
好人? 好人?
Sweet? Sweet?
瞧瞧我!
Look at me!
他暴揍我那时,像个好人吗?
Was he sweet when he gave me
the most savage beating of my life?
- 可你是歹徒啊!
- Babe!
-You were mugging me!
-Babe!
相信我,世界上没有那么好的人!
No one is as good as this guy's pretending to be.
别傻了!
Don't be a sucker.
不该这么对他的
He doesn't deserve this.
他也不该得到你!
He doesn't deserve you.
我的脖子!
My neck!
他们让我觉得自己是个傻瓜, Jan.
I feel like an idiot.
They made me look like a fool, Jan.
我真想把"深入追击"的...
I was thinking of going down
to that lnside Access place...
...那个Mac McGrath揪出来痛打一顿
...and giving Mac McGrath
the beating of a lifetime.
听起来不错,但你犯不着和他们一样
That sounds like fun,
but don't stoop to their level.
你比那些人好一万倍, Deedsy.
You're better than that, Deedsy.
所以,不要理会他们
我们永远在这里支持你
So hang in there.
And know that we are always here for you.
谢谢你, Jan.
我叔公开的公司确实非常了不起
Thanks, Jan.
My uncle really built an amazing company.
他为5万人提供了工作
Because of him, 50,000 people have jobs.
他还经常做许多好事
And he always tried to do the right thing.
这么说, 他是个很不错的人
Well, he does sound amazing.
别忘了, 你很像他!
But don't forget, he was related to you.
别再说那些了,说说关于那个女孩儿的事
Enough about that. Tell me more about this girl.
她很不错, 和我一样, 来自一个小镇
She's nice, a small-town kid, like me.
Deeds, 你这个变态的混球....
Deedsy, you sick-ass mo' fo'....
你还不抓紧时间,不然她就跟别人跑了
You got to tap that
before she starts boning other guys, kid.
Boo-Yah!
他以为是你写的!
He thinks it's you! He thinks it's you!
- 来吧,Cedar. 打起精神来
- 接球吧
-Let's go, Cedar. Put some steam on it, kid.
-Here it comes.
嘿,你想谋杀我呀,你真有两下子!
He's trying to kill me. You're good at this.
你约我打球,我以为你会打
When you asked me to play,
I thought you'd done this before.
Johnny McEnroe 说这玩意儿很简单
No, Johnny McEnroe said it was wicked easy.
而且我叔公也很喜欢,对吧?
Plus, it was my uncle's favorite game, right?
- 你怎么知道的?
- 从他日记里读到的
-How'd you know that?
-I read it in his diary.
是吗?
Really?
我不知道他还写日记
I didn't know he kept a diary.
抱歉,伙计
Sorry about that, dude.
没关系, 那家伙刚加入
It's okay. He's a new member.
球童!
Ball boy.
Ball boy!
来吧, 我准备好了
All right, baby, I'm ready for you.
你还好吧?
You okay?
- 小意思 !
- Anderson, 你一定在偷着高兴,是吧?
-Not a problem.
-Anderson, you liked that, didn't you?
是的
I did.
听着, Deeds, 有个好消息
Listen, Deeds, I got some good news.
那些文件明天就可以签字了
Those papers will be ready to sign tomorrow.
一方面,你可以放心,你叔公的公司
有了一个好的归宿...
So you can relax knowing
your uncle's company'll be in good hands...
...同时,你也是一个身价400亿的富翁了.
...and you can go home $40 billion richer.
我正打算,或许多逗留几天...
I was thinking about
maybe sticking around here...
- 和你们一起开开会什么的
- 什么?
-...and going to some meetings with you.
-What?
失误!
Fault!
我想我可以学着管理公司,就像打网球一样
I figured I could learn, like this tennis thing.
我发誓,我不是有意的
I swear to God, I'm not trying to do that.
我不是必须卖掉自己的股份,对吧?
I don't got to sell my shares right away, do I?
还有,Cedar.
我认识了一个女孩儿, 我们很合得来
Plus, I met this girl, Cedar.
I swear to God, I think she's the one.
你们一定很开心
That's wonderful for you.
正中咽喉 ? 不会吧 ?
That got you right in the throat, huh?
我得问问你, 如果我打中你, 是谁得分?
Got to ask you, though, if it hits you,
is it my point or yours?
- 你
- 这么说,我赢了
-Yours.
-I'm winning then, I guess.
"浴室面谈 , 关于Deeds"?
"Deeds info, meet in shower"?
老天!
Sweet Jesus!
你是谁? 想谈什么?
Who are you? And what do you want to tell me?
我是 "深入追击" 的制作人
I'm a junior producer at lnside Access.
我有些关于Deeds的消息, 可以帮你把他弄走,
有兴趣么?
I have information that will help you
get Deeds out of town. Interested?
好啊,看看你有什么消息,
拜托别洗你的臀部了
Very. Provided the information is good
and you stop soaping your ass.
- 知道Deeds的女朋友么?
- 那个学校护士
-You know Deeds' girlfriend?
-The school nurse.
不完全正确
Not quite.
Lucy, 帮我把昨晚的稿子拿来
J.D. 会告诉你在哪儿
Lucy, bring me the overnights.
J.D. will tell you where they are.
喂,你坐在我的椅子上干嘛呢?
Hey. What the hell are you doing in my chair?
Chuck Cedar
Chuck Cedar.
或许咱们可以合作一下
I think you and I could help each other out.
- 感觉兴奋么?
- 非常兴奋
-You excited about this trip?
-I'm so excited.
- 你带我去哪儿?
- 我说过, 这是个惊喜
-Where are you taking me?
-I told you, that's a surprise.
怎么样?
Well?
"Winchestertonfieldville, 爱荷华"
"Winchestertonfieldville, lowa."
简直他妈的开玩笑!
You got to be shitting me.
我从没听过你说粗话
I never heard you curse before.
我太兴奋了!
I'm that excited!
各位Winchestertonfieldvillians 的居民,
还认得出这个女孩儿吗?
All you Winchestertonfieldvillians,
recognize this little girl?
给大家一点提示,
"从Radley家的苹果树上摔下来...
I'll give you a hint.
"I fell out of Boo Radley's apple tree...
"...胳膊疼的要命!"
"...and my arm is killing me!"
快看看,这是小Pammy Dawson呀!
Come on, it's little Pammy Dawson!
大家好
Hello.
你和Bill Dawson有什么关系吗?
You related to Bill Dawson?
是的,我们是亲戚
Yes, he's my relative.
我好像想起来了
I think I remember you.
你以前是不是有些驼背?
Did you used to have a hump on your back?
- 没错,那一定是我了,我的确有一点点驼背
- 是吗?
-Yes, that was me. I had a slight hump.
-Really?
那可不是什么"一点点驼背" !
This was no slight hump.
我说的那个女孩,后背和骆驼差不多
The girl I'm thinking of looked like
she had a damn beach ball on her back.
是的,的确是驼背的很厉害,
不过我不太喜欢别人提起罢了
Okay, it was a huge hump
and I'm a little sensitive about it.
快瞧,Martha, 是"卡西莫多", 长这么大了!
Look, Martha, it's Quasimodo, all growed up.
太好了,我还以为你死了呢
How wonderful! I thought you died.
她现在是个护士了
She actually became a school nurse.
- 你是护士?
- 没错
-You're a nurse?
-Yes.
这个毛病该怎么治?
What should I do about this?
- 还是让Pepper医生来看看吧
- 谁?
-I would call Dr. Pepper.
-Who?
非常高兴见到大家, 我们该走了!
It was so great seeing everybody again.
We're going to leave now.
再见
'Bye.
- 你好,邮递员先生
- 早上好
-Hi, mailman.
-'Morning.
你们好吗?
How you doing?
快看, 就是那座了
Oh, my God, there it is.
蓝色的百叶窗, 红色大门 , 轮胎做的秋千
那就是你们家了,对不对?
Blue shutters, red door, tire swing.
That's your house, isn't it?
你这么肯定?
Wouldn't you know it?
来,去看看
Come on.
大家好 , 你们知道她是谁吗 ?
How you guys doing? You know who she is?
她以前在这里住过,那时她还是个小姑娘
She used to live in this house
when she was a little girl.
是这样的
It's true.
你们住过同一所房子, 差不多该算是亲戚了
You live here and she used to live here.
You're practically cousins.
令我想起了很多
So many memories.
从何说起呢?
Where to begin?
这是壁炉...
This is our fireplace...
...我父亲会烧木头...
...where my dad would build fires...
...生火
...out of wood.
这是饭厅,我们在这儿吃饭...
And this is the dining room,
where we would have our meals...
...和做饭
...made of food.
这是我弟弟的房间
And this was my brother's room.
我父母不喜欢我弟弟
My parents hated my brother.
这座房子是我爸爸6年前亲手建的
My daddy built this house
with his bare hands six years ago.
你爸爸在骗人
Your daddy is a liar.
你为什么 --
How come you--
他呛住了, 咱们快走吧
He's choking. We should go.
- 救命啊
- 你说什么呀?
-Help.
-What are you talking about?
- 你是个护士,快帮帮他
- 救救他!
-You're the nurse, help him.
-Save him!
- 让开,孩子们
- 他要死了!
-Stand back, kids.
-He's gonna die!
- 送他去医院吧!
- 把它拍出来!
-Take him to the hospital!
-Smack it out!
- 救救他!
- 把它弄出来!
-Save him!
-Get it out of him!
救救他, 求你了!
Save him, please!
- 真没想到
- 谢谢
-That was amazing.
-Thank you.
我救了他
I saved his life.
你真了不起, Dawson护士
You're my hero, Nurse Dawson.
谢谢了
Thank you, thank you.
- 好厉害的停车技术,伙计
- 谢谢, Deeds.
-Good parking job, buddy.
-Thanks, Deeds.
试音, 试音
Testing, testing.
我真的太高兴了
I had such a wonderful time.
谢谢你, 多么美妙的一天
Thank you for such a great day.
- 谢谢你带我参观你的故乡
- 希望有机会能去你的故乡看看
-Thanks for showing me your town.
-I hope sometime to see your hometown.
也许,有一天这里会成为我的新故乡
Maybe someday this will be my new hometown.
Deeds.
- 有些事我想告诉你
- 什么事?
-There's something I have to tell you.
-What's the matter?
怎么了?
What?
回新汉普郡,做个快乐的有钱人吧!
Go back to New Hampshire and enjoy being rich.
别再...
Just...
...别让自己再受到伤害, 好吗?
...don't let anyone hurt you anymore, okay?
混蛋
Sucker.
Pam.
我给你写了张卡
I made a card for you.
可能很愚蠢
It's kind of dumb.
但我已经尽了最大的努力, 请不要笑话我
I never worked on anything harder, though,
so don't laugh at me.
记得那晚我们去餐厅...
Remember we went to the restaurant
that first night...
...你点了奶酪烤鸡?
...and you ordered chicken parmesan?
所以我给你画了一碟
So I drew you a plate.
里面有鸡肉和奶酪...
There's the chicken and the cheese...
...还有意大利面条. 弯弯曲曲的
花了我不少时间
...and the linguini. That took me
a long time with the squigglies.
很漂亮!
It's beautiful.
里面还有一首诗!
There's a poem inside for you.
"无法呼吸, 仿佛身在半空"
"Hard to breathe, feels like floating
"爱意荡漾, 怎将它心中锁"
"So full of love my heart's exploding
"如何启齿, 该怎把话儿说"
"Mouth is dry, hands are shaking
"毫无保留, 为你燃烧这爱之火"
"My heart is yours for the taking
"手足无措, 那不是真的我"
"Acting weird, not myself
"与你共舞, 仿佛梦幻中时光交错"
"Dancing around like the Keebler elf"
真不错!
That was funny.
"如愿以偿"
"Finally time for this poor schlub
"原来,爱的滋味令人着魔"
"to know how it feels to fall in lub"
我找不到其他可以压韵的字
I couldn't think of anything else
that rhymes with "schlub."
所以只好用了个"魔"字...
"Rub" and "tub" didn't work.
对不起, Deeds.
I'm sorry, Deeds.
- 我真的很抱歉
- 用不着抱歉 ,我不明白
-I'm really sorry.
-Don't be sorry, that was unbelievable.
Hi, Finch小姐.... Atticus.
Hi, Mrs. Finch.... Atticus.
晚安
Sleep well.
- Al, 我走路回去
- 好的, Deeds.
-Al, I'm gonna walk home.
-Okay, Deeds.
我爱纽约!
I love New York!
没人在乎!
Nobody cares!
我爱上他了
I'm in love with him.
我今晚会去见他, 把一切都告诉他
I'm going to see him tonight
and tell him everything.
- 或许他会揍你一顿的
- 那样我会好过些
-He'll probably punch you in the face.
-I kind of hope he does.
别这样, Babe, 振作点
Come on, Babe, snap out of it.
你真的愿意为那个笨蛋而放弃一切吗?
You really want to throw all this away
for a dipshit like that?
他不是笨蛋, 他心地善良
他之所以被误解,
He's not a dipshit. He's a goodhearted guy
who we think is a weirdo...
是因为他并不认同我们那种
冷嘲热讽、漠不关心
...because he doesn't share
our sense of ironic detachment.
- 那种颓废、卑鄙、自作聪明
- 胡说八道?
-All this hip, snide, smart-alecky--
-Bullshit?
对，还有胡说八道
Yes, bullshit.
好吧，等一会儿, 我会穿上我的名牌大衣
Well, in a few moments,
I'll put on my Versace overcoat...
开着昂贵的名车, 回到
我第五大街的豪华公寓...
...get into my Mercedes,
drive to my Fifth Avenue apartment...
...然后和我的女朋友风花雪月
...and squeeze my girlfriend's big, fake boobs.
全因为刚才你说的那些陋习,
我拥有了这一切
And that bullshit you're talking about
paid for all of it.
真替你高兴,Mac. 但我还是得告诉他
Good for you, Mac. But I'm still telling him.
好吧....
Well....
Babe Bennett 坠入爱河了
Babe Bennett falls in love.
我为你感到高兴,真的
I'm happy for you. I am.
我会想念你的, Babe.
Gonna miss you, Babe.
真舍不得你
Something fierce.
她会喜好么?
You think she'll like this?
明白
All right.
奶酪烤鸡? 不错,谢谢你!
Chicken parmesan? Terrific, thank you.
让我听听
Let's hear it.
- 她会喜欢的, Deeds先生
- 好的
-She gonna like that, Mr. Deeds.
-Okay.
- Emilio, 布置的真漂亮
- 谢谢你
-Emilio, it looks beautiful.
-Thank you.
这些花好像太高了, 我都看不见她了
These roses might be a little too high.
I won't be able to see her.
- 换些小的好吗?
- 好的,先生
-Do we have anything smaller?
-Yes, sir.
Okay.
Byron?
非常好
That's terrific.
- 能陪我坐一会儿么?
- 好的,先生
-Would you mind sitting for a second?
-Yes, sir.
说点什么, 假装你就是她
Say something to me. Pretend you're her.
- 我,先生?
- 求你了
-Me, sir?
-Please.
好吧...
Well...
...谢谢你今晚邀请我共进晚餐
...it's nice of you to have invited me
to dine with you this evening.
我很荣幸
It's my pleasure.
你太高了, 能不能坐低一点?
Actually, you're too tall. Can you slink down?
- 像这样?
- 好多了
-Like this?
-That's good.
这是我感觉最美妙的约会
This is one of the best dates I've ever been on.
我有一种很特别的感觉
You make me feel very special.
我也是
You make me feel very special, too.
我有件东西想送给你
That's why I got this for you.
来, 靠近一点
Okay, lean forward.
- 我非常喜欢你
- 我也喜欢你
-I really like you a lot.
-I like you, too.
- 我每时每刻都在想你
-I can't stop thinking about you.
求你, 让我摸摸你的脚吧 !
Please let me touch your feet.
好了, 到此为止吧, 你可以走了!
Okay, this is getting weird.
You can stand up now.
- Deeds!
- 伙计们!
-Deeds!
-Fellows!
今天是你的大日子,我们来助助兴
We wanted to come and wish you
the best on your big night.
谢谢你们,我现在紧张死了,
这辈子第一次求婚
Thanks a lot. I'm so nervous.
I never asked anybody to marry me before.
现在是7:30, "深入追击"播出的时间
It's 7:30, time for lnside Access.
这次不会再有什么令人尴尬的消息了吧?
We're not in for any more
nasty surprises, are we?
我想不会的,我整天都在这儿,
什么蠢事都没做过
I don't think so. I haven't done
anything stupid all day. I've been here.
那我们来看看他们还有什么新花样儿 ?
Let's see what lame show they put on
when they don't have Deeds to pick on.
劳驾!
Excuse me!
- 请转到八频道 ?
- 没问题
-Could you put on Channel 8, please?
-You got it.
欢迎收看"深入追击", 我是Mac McGrath.
Welcome to lnside Access. I'm Mac McGrath.
一直以来, 我们的传媒都有一种值得自豪的能力
All of us here at I. A. take pride
in our ability to handle...
那就是对新闻事件十分敏锐和投入
...every story with sensitivity and empathy...
Okay, pal.
...但同时又能够保持足够的专业距离
...while maintaining
an appropriate journalistic distance.
但是如果一个记者陷入自己报道的事件而
不能自拔, 又会如何?
But what happens when a reporter
becomes part of what she's reporting?
如果一个记者爱上了一个白痴呢?
What happens when a journalist
falls in love with an idiot?
你看到的是Longfellow Deeds 和 Pam Dawson.
That's Longfellow Deeds with Pam Dawson.
- 竟然连她都不放过
- 一个学校护士...
-I can't believe they involved her in this.
-A school nurse...
...刚刚从爱荷华州的Winchestertonfieldville镇
移居纽约
...who recently moved to New York City
from Winchestertonfieldville, lowa.
慢着! 这位Pam Dawson
好像和 Babe Bennett 惊人的相象 ?
But wait. Doesn't Pam Dawson
bear a striking resemblance to...
而后者是我们"深入追击"的一位制作人员
...Babe Bennett,
a producer here at lnside Access?
事实上 , 她们根本就是一个人
In fact, the two are one and the same.
我们将为您送上最新的偷拍影像
We'll wire your apartment
with state-of-the-art surveillance video.
Sounds good.
Deeds.
我来是想解释清楚
I came here to try to explain.
我是全世界最蠢的白痴
I'm the biggest sucker in the world.
这个城市有时是很残忍的
This town can be brutal.
我不属于这里
I don't belong here.
我不会管理公司, 甚至不会管理自己的生活
I can't run the company,
I can't even run my own life.
别这么说,
还有个好消息, 文件已经准备好了
Sure you can.
The good news is the papers are ready.
你一签字, 我们买回股票, 而你得到400亿美元
Once you sign them, we'll get our stock
and you'll get your $40 billion.
我不想要, 捐给慈善机构吧
I don't want that money. Just give it to a charity.
- 哪个比较好?
- 黑人高等教育基金会?
-What's a good charity?
-The United Negro College Fund?
好吧, 就给他们吧
Okay, give it to those guys.
我们送你去机场好吗 ? 让公司的直升机送你回家
Can we give you a ride to the airport?
The company chopper will take you home.
多谢了 , 我还是自己走吧
Thanks, anyway. I'll be all right on my own.
- 很高兴认识大家
- 很高兴认识你, Deeds.
-Nice meeting you all.
-Nice meeting you, Deeds.
再见!
Goodbye!
再见了
Goodbye.
怎么会这样!
It's not right.
你一定是Jan了. 我是--
You must be Jan. My name is--
我知道, 你不就是那个五行欠打的Dawson么
I know who you are. Wham-bam Dawson.
那个无情无义的小娼妇!
A. k. a. Little Miss Slut-Slut.
没错, 骂得对 !
Okay, I deserve that.
你知道他被你伤害得多深吗?
Do you have any idea how much you hurt him?
我决不会让你再骚扰他
You're not getting anywhere near that boy.
我一定要找到他, 无论如何
I have to find him and there's nothing
you can do to stop me.
- 你不妨试试看
- 我要告诉他我有多伤心
-There's a lot I can do to stop you.
-He needs to know how bad I feel.
就算找遍天涯海角...
And that I would go to the end of the earth...
无论付出什么代价, 我也要弥补我的过错
...I would do anything
to take back what I did to him.
真抱歉, 你说什么都没用!
I'm sorry, all I heard was,
"Blah, blah, I'm a dirty tramp."
我跟你说, 只要过得了我这关...
Tell you what. You get by me...
...我就告诉你他在哪儿
...I'll tell you where he is.
放马过来 !
Feeling crazy!
来吧小乖乖
Come to Mama.
我在斗牛场干过6年 ,
你得加把劲才行了
I was a rodeo clown for six years.
You'll have to step it up a notch, shorty.
这招怎么样 ?
You mean like this?
你踢我那儿干嘛 ?
我又没有 "小弟弟" !
Where were you kicking?
I ain't got no balls, dummy!
起来 !
Get up!
- 把我放下 !
- 没问题 !
-Put me down!
-You got it!
- 你就告诉我Deeds在哪里吧!
- 你别跑啊
-Just tell me where Deeds is.
-Bring your bony ass over here.
我要把你大卸八块拿去喂狗!
I want to cut you into eight slices of bitch-eroni.
你没事吧 ?
Are you all right?
踢得漂亮, 踢得漂亮 !
Good kick, honey. Good kick.
鬼眼 !
Crazy Eyes!
- 给你
-All right.
-Here you go.
花生酱加糖豆, 真是绝配 !
Peanut butter and gumballs. Nice combo.
别太难过了, 时间可以医治一切创伤
Don't worry about what happened.
Time heals all things.
除了这双鬼眼
Except these crazy eyes.
是啊, 回家后我感觉好多了
It's good to be home. I know that much.
我不是说你, Deeds.
我是对那只松鼠说的
I wasn't talking to you, Deeds.
I was talking to that squirrel over there.
那个叫Cedar的家伙实在不是什么好东西...
Although it's a shame about that Cedar fellow...
...他要分拆你叔公的公司,
解雇所有的员工
...tearing apart your uncle's company
and firing all those nice people.
你从哪听说的?
Where'd you hear that?
我整天都看股市频道
I watch the stock market channel all the time.
因为我怀疑有个主持人可能
是个邪恶的妖精
I just watch because I suspect that anchorman
of being an evil leprechaun.
他骗得了别人, 骗不了我
He can bullshit everybody else,
but he ain't fooling me.
是那儿了
There it is.
来人哪!
Someone!
救命啊!
Help!
Deeds! 救命!
Deeds! Help!
Deeds! 救救我!
上帝啊! Deeds!
Oh, God! Deeds!
Oh, 上帝!
Oh, my God!
这回摄像机藏在哪儿? 树林里吗?
Where do you got the camera hidden,
in the woods?
没有摄像机
No camera.
我冻死了, 求你!
I'm so cold. Please!
这次没歹徒袭击你了?
You gonna get mugged in there, too?
我对...
I'm so...
...对不起你
...sorry.
我是真的爱你
I really love you.
你胡扯!
Bullshit!
我来了!
I'm coming!
退后点! 退后 !
Go down! Go down!
铁脚来了
Here comes the black foot.
不!
No!
抓住我的脚, 别管难不难看了
I know it's gross, but grab it.
快上来, 没事了
I got you. I got you.
- 上帝, 你的脚可真恶心!
- 我知道, 我知道, 起来吧
-Oh, God, your foot is disgusting!
-I know, I know. Come here.
你怎么样? 没事吧 ?
Come on, you okay? You okay?
没事
I think so.
你没从苹果树上摔下来过 ?
You didn't really fall out of an apple tree,
did you?
没有
No.
但我是真的爱你
But I really love you.
可我连你是谁都不知道
I don't even know who you are.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我十分抱歉!
I am so sorry.
Preston Blake留下的庞大公司
将会四分五裂, 并被拍卖
A company in tatters. Preston Blake's
great legacy gone to the highest bidder.
根据经Chuck Cedar证实的消息,
The shocking announcement from Chuck Cedar
today confirmed that Blake Media...
Blake媒体公司将被分拆后出售
...will be stripped down
and sold off piece by piece.
唯一有能力反对Cedar先生, 并挽救
该公司的人---Longfellow Deeds
The only man who could stand up
to Mr. Cedar and save the company...
已经放弃投票权, 离开了纽约
...Longfellow Deeds, has apparently
given up his voting rights and left the city.
在明天召开的股东大会上,
The sale's expected to pass
with unanimous consent...
拍卖公司的决议很可能会顺利通过
...at the annual stockholders' meeting
here in New York tomorrow afternoon.
另有消息证实,Blake公司的5万名员工...
Sources indicate that virtually
all of Blake's 50,000 employees...
很可能会失业
...are likely to lose their jobs.
慢着, 我也是Blake公司的员工
Wait a minute. I'm a Blake employee.
老天, 太糟糕了!
Holy shit! This sucks.
女士们先生们, 事实上, 这次公司的出售
Ladies and gentlemen,
the bottom line is that this divestiture...
将会使每个股东, 包括我本人
...will result in every shareholder,
all of you and myself included...
手中的持有的股份价值不菲
...getting a substantial premium for our shares.
但在投票之前, 根据公司的章程
But before we vote, the company bylaws
require me to open the floor...
我必须听取各位股东对该计划的各种意见
...to shareholders for statements
either for or against this buyout plan.
有哪位想发言 ?
Does anyone wish to make a statement?
毁掉这间公司, 是对一个杰出人物的侮辱!
Dismantling this company
would be an insult to a great man.
你吓了我一跳
You scared me.
这是无法容忍的可怕罪行
It is an unspeakable outrage
and it cannot be allowed to happen.
对不起, 我想说两句
Excuse me. I got a statement.
Longfellow Deeds.
非常不幸 , 你已经卖掉了自己的300万股份
Unfortunately, since you sold me
your 300 million shares...
- 所以你无权在这里发言
- 不幸的是你
-...you've no right to speak at this meeting.
-Unfortunately for you...
我今早买了一股Blake媒体的股份
...I bought one share of Blake Media
this morning.
你告诉过我, 每个股东都有发言权
You told me every stockholder
has a say in this company.
无论大小
Even the little guy.
好吧, 给你两分钟
别忘了, 我拥有百分之四十九的股权
You have two minutes, but remember,
I control 49 percent of this company.
所以, 你差不多要说服所有其他股东
You're gonna have to persuade
just about everyone else...
...放弃到手的钞票!
...to start hating money.
大家好,我是 Deeds.
Hello, everybody. I'm Deeds.
我曾经是本公司最大的股东, 不过只是短短几天
For a little while, I was a big part of this company.
那时我非常富有,大权在握
I was wicked rich and powerful.
有钱和权力并不是一件坏事
Now being rich and powerful isn't a bad thing.
而且那边的先生们似乎对此极为热衷
It looks like the Monopoly guy over there
is pretty darned psyched about it.
但问题是, 如果为了金钱和权力
But the problem is
what can happen when you decide...
不择手段会怎么样呢 ?
...that you would do absolutely anything
to become rich and powerful.
我不清楚你为什么心血来潮
I don't know who licked the red off
your lollipop today...
但你一定是选错了讲道的地方
...but you are preaching to the wrong choir.
我想说的是,
All I'm saying is, when you were kids...
你们小时候是否梦想过将来会成为
...did you dream
about becoming a savvy investor one day...
一个惟利是图的商人 ?
...who would think with his wallet
instead of his heart?
最起码, 我没有
Come on, I know I didn't.
我想当一个消防员
I wanted to be a fireman.
我想作一个帮别人解决困难的人
I wanted to be the guy everybody called on
if they were in trouble.
我希望能帮助别人
I wanted to help people...
当然, 从那些杆子上滑下来也挺有意思
...and yeah, I wanted to slide down
those wicked awesome poles.
而钱, 我总是最后才考虑
But money,
that was the last thing I thought about.
你呢, 先生 ?
你想过当个消防员吗 ?
What about you, sir?
Did you want to be a fireman?
没有
No, I did not.
说实话, 我曾经想当一个兽医
Truth be told, I wanted to be a veterinarian.
不错, 你为什么想当兽医 ?
Cool. Why would you want to do that?
- 我希望能帮助生病的动物
- 那你现在是干什么的?
-I wanted to help sick animals.
-And what do you do now?
我经营连锁屠宰场
I own a chain of slaughterhouses.
这好像和你的初衷背道而驰了吧?
You kind of went the other way
on that one, didn't you?
Okay.
坐在后面的人, 请告诉我你的梦想
In the back. Come on.
Tell me what you wanted to be.
我想作一个魔术师 !
I wanted to be a magician.
- 那你现在做什么?
- 我经营一个色情网站
-And what do you do now?
-I operate a pornographic website.
我想, 那至少也能给某些人带来快乐,
不过不太光彩罢了
That makes people happy also, I guess.
But kind of in a grosser way.
- 还有谁 ?
- 我想作个议员
-Who else?
-I wanted to be a senator.
- 我想开花店
- 做闻名世界的煎饼
-I wanted to be a florist.
-International House Pancake.
我想作个男人
I wanted to be a man.
原来如此
That explains a lot.
我想作乒乓球冠军
I wanted to be a Ping-Pong champion.
但是, 你们没有实现自己的梦想, 对不对?
But you're not those things
you wanted to be, are you?
我们一次一次的向现实妥协...
Everybody made a compromise,
then another compromise, and now...
而现在, 你们正打算令5万人失去工作!
只是为了赚点快钱?
...you're about to put 50,000 people out of work,
to make a quick buck? Come on.
如果你们儿时的自己知道了今天的事儿
I bet if we ran into the 6th-grade versions
of ourselves right now...
我敢打赌, 他们一定会把你们折腾个半死
...they would kick our asses
and put Bubble Yum in our hair...
甚至不能容忍你们有这样的想法
...for even thinking about doing this.
没错, 我会把自己痛打一顿
He's right. I would've beat my greedy ass red.
我会让自己从旋转木马上飞出去!
I would've thrown myself off the merry-go-round.
我会把自己赤身裸体绑在椅子上,再用烟头烫 !
I would've tied myself naked to a chair
and burned myself with lit cigarettes.
这儿有人想过当心理医生吗 ?
Did anyone here dream
of becoming a psychiatrist?
开玩笑罢了, 朋友
Just kidding, pal.
现在还有机会挽救我们的童真 !
There's still hope for the kids inside of all of us.
请不要拆分我叔公的公司
Please don't break up my uncle's company.
我一直都想试试这个
I always wanted to do that.
不错...
Well...
...说的非常动情, Deeds.
...that was very touching, Deeds.
似乎拍卖的决议被否决了 ?
It appears this divestiture has been defeated.
不过我好像忘了一件事
Unless I'm forgetting something.
我自己的300万股份...
My 300 million votes...
再加上我为外国投资者代理的5万股
...plus the five million votes I control
as proxy for the foreign investors.
有了这百分之五十一的股份, 我该如何投票呢?
So which way should I vote my 51 percent?
我投赞成票 !
I vote aye.
305万票, 赞成!
305 million times.
赞成票获胜, Blake媒体公司不复存在了
The ayes have it. And Blake Media is no more.
别那么着急, Chuck.
Not so fast, Chuck.
你有麻烦了, 我小的时候,
一直想作个好记者
Too bad for you, when I was a kid,
I wanted to be a good reporter.
Bennett小姐, 我可不知道你也是股东
Miss Bennett,
I wasn't aware you were a stockholder.
你不知道的事儿还多着呢 !
There's a couple things you're not aware of.
比如说修眉毛
How to tweeze your eyebrows, for instance.
还有, 那就是: 当Deeds 放弃他的财产时,
那些财产其实并不属于他
Also, when Deeds gave away his fortune,
he gave away something that wasn't his.
- 你在说什么?
- 我手头有Preston Blake的日记
-What are you talking about?
-I have here the diary of Preston Blake.
是我偷来看的
I stole it and read it.
请别生气, 我是为了干好事 , 我保证
Please don't be mad at me.
I did it for good reasons, I promise.
我想在这里读一段Blake先生的日记
I would like to read a passage
from Mr. Blake's diary...
日期是: 1957年4月12日
...dated April 12, 1957.
" 我的欲望就要爆发
"I am a volcano of lust.
" 依靠心灵的指引, 我取得了事业的成功 "
"I've gotten this far in business
by following my heart.
" 如今, 它要再一次帮助我 "
"And I must follow it now...
" 寻找真爱 ! "
"...in love.
"只要她给我一个暗示, 一个机会"
"If she just gives me a sign, an opening."
要我帮您擦擦这些树叶么,Blake先生?
Want me to wipe the leaves
on your ficus tree, Mr. Blake?
你可以叫我Preston
You can call me Preston.
要我帮您擦树叶么, Preston?
Want me to wipe the leaves
on your ficus tree, Preston?
好的
Yes.
好的 ！
Yes!
那位神秘的女士是谁 ?
Who was this mystery woman?
这是Blake公司1957年4月的出入登记本
I have here the Blake Media ledger
sign-in book from April, 1957.
12号那晚, 只有一个女工在Blake所在的那层上班
On the night of the 12th, there was
only one woman working on Blake's floor.
不幸的是, 9个月之后, 她就去世了,
死于难产 !
Sadly, nine months later, she died,
giving birth to a son.
留下了一个男孩...
A son born...
...那天是1958年1月23日
...January 23, 1958.
那是我的生日!
That is my birthday.
Consuela Lopez小姐
To Miss Consuela Lopez.
那是我母亲!
That is my mother.
你才是400亿美元遗产的合法继承人!
And the rightful heir to $40 billion!
那是我的钱 ?
That is my money?
只需要一个简单的 DNA 测试就能证明
A simple DNA test will show...
Emilio Lopez 才是Blake媒体公司的最大股东
...that Emilio Lopez is the majority stockholder
to Blake Media.
- 那是我的钱!
- 是你的钱!
-It is my money!
-That's your money!
是我的钱 !
That is my money!
Way to go, Emilio!
我会为大家办好事的
I will do good things for everyone.
免费佛来明哥舞课程 !
Free flamenco lessons for all.
各位, 各位! 请静一静!
People, people! Please!
- 那是我的钱
- 别被误导, 那都是骗人的
-That is my money.
-Don't be misled. These are all lies.
Cedar...
Mr. Cedar...
... 你被解雇了
...you are fired.
你无权解雇我 !
You can't fire me!
我才是老板 !
I'm in control!
放开我 ! 我是 Chuck Cedar!
Get your hands off me! I'm Chuck Cedar!
那次, 在湖上你救了我...
At the lake, when you saved my life...
我还没机会谢谢你
...which I never got a chance
to properly thank you for--
- 别客气
- 你说你还不知道我是谁
-You're welcome.
-You said you didn't know who I was.
我突然意识到, 连我自己都不知道
And it made me realize I don't know who I am.
于是我决定要重新认识自己,
这是我目前的成果:
So I started working on it
and here's what I got so far.
我叫Babe Bennett.
我出生在长岛的Syossett
My name is Babe Bennett.
I grew up in Syossett, Long lsland.
我的眼睛是褐色, 不过我已经不记得
头发原来的颜色了
I have brown eyes and I don't know
what my natural hair color is anymore.
5年级时, 我极度崇拜Walter Cronkite.
When I was in 5th grade,
I got a crush on Walter Cronkite.
我跟你说的那个小本子是真的
And I really did have that Holly Hobby notebook
I was telling you about.
我喜欢Bruce Springsteen, Almond Roca的歌
还有Abbott 和 Costello 演的电影
I love Bruce Springsteen, Almond Roca
and Abbott and Costello movies.
我不喜欢甘草和自己的脚踝
I don't like licorice or my ankles.
最重要的是, 我明白自己干了蠢事
More importantly,
I know that I messed up real bad.
我愿意用一辈子的时间...
And I'd be willing to spend the rest of my life...
来请求你再给我一次机会
...begging you to give me another chance...
因为我深深的爱着你
...because I am so deeply in love with you...
我知道那是永远不变的爱
...and I know it's definitely
that forever kind of love--
你一定是疯了
You're crazy.
你的脚踝很漂亮
You have beautiful ankles.
咱们回家吧
Let's go home.
你被解雇了! 还有你 ! 你 ! 你 !
You're fired! You! You!
Oh, 你,先生, 我一定要炒了你
Oh, you, sir. You are definitely fired.
我希望能留下, 如果能再有一次机会,
我会做些好事的
I'd like to stay. I think I can really do
some good if I just got another chance.
可以不解雇, 但明早你要让我帮你换袜子
Not fired. But tomorrow morning,
you let me change your socks.
好的
Okay.
至于你, Long-Long-Longfellow...
And you, Long-Long-Longfellow...
是你让这一切成为现实的
...you are the one who made all this possible...
以你美妙的话语和善良的心灵
...with your beautiful words
and your beautiful spirit.
还有Bennett小姐, 了不起的调查工作
And Miss Bennett, with her beautiful research.
我该怎么感谢你呢 ?
How can I thank you?
有你的友谊就足够了, Emilio.
你是个好人
All I want is your friendship, Emilio.
You're a good man.
我会想你的
I'll miss you.
Deeds!
- 我给你10亿美元好吗 ?
- 好吧
-How about $1 billion?
-All right.
成交
Done.
天哪!
Holy Jeez!
难以置信!
I can't believe it!
- 什么事?
- Hallmark公司的回信
-What's that?
-A letter from Hallmark.
他们真的要买我的一张卡
They're actually going to buy one of my cards.
- 太好了! 是哪张?
- 我写给你的那张, 还记得吗?
-My gosh! Which one?
-The one I wrote for you, remember it?
我记得吗 ?
Do I remember?
"无法呼吸, 仿佛身在半空"
"Hard to breathe, feels like floating
"爱意荡漾, 怎将它心中锁"
"So full of love my heart's exploding
"如何启齿, 该怎把话儿说"
"Mouth is dry, hands are shaking
"毫无保留, 为你燃烧这爱之火"
"My heart is yours for the taking
"手足无措, 那不是真的我"
"Acting weird, not myself
"与你共舞, 仿佛梦幻中时光交错"
"Dancing around like the Keebler elf
"如愿以偿"
"Finally time for this poor schlub
"原来,爱的滋味令人着魔"
"to know how it feels to fall in lub"
我以你为荣!
I'm so proud of you!
简直不敢相信, Deeds给我们每人买了一辆
Can you believe Deeds bought us all these?
妈的, 这玩意儿真够快的!
Damn, these things are fast!
我没事儿!
I'm okay!
Subtitle Revised by HchC